主演：梅格·瑞恩
主演：休·杰克曼
片名：隔世情缘
时间,已经被提为第四度空间.
Time, it has been proposed is the fourth dimension.
And yet, for mortal man,time has no dimension at all.
但是到现在,对凡人来讲,时间并没有更多的尺度可言.
We are like horses with blinders seeing only what lies before us.
我们就像带着眼罩的马,只能看到我们面前的东西.
Forever guessing the future...
听,听.永远只能猜测未来,
...and fabricating the past.
拼凑过去.-是他.-谁?
- Brilliant. Quite right, Your Grace.
天才.完全正确,阁下
How, you ask, can we lift these shackles and live not in the moment..
你们也许要问,我们怎能
挣脱这些銍酷而生活在广袤的,辉煌的时间的延续中?
...but in the glorious expanse of time's continuum?
听着,我将要告诉你们.
Listen, and I shall tell you.
秘密就藏在我们持久完成的动力之中.
The secret lies in the enduring power of our achievements...
我们的创造力!
- Yes! - ...our creations!
As the pyramids testify to the Egyptians...
就像是古埃及金字塔已经被证实
so my glorious erection shall represent...
伫立的辉煌将永久代表
...our culture in perpetuity.
我们的文化.
Behold, rising before you the greatest erection on the continent.
看啊,在你们后面正在升起的大陆上一个最伟大的建筑.
The greatest erection of the age!
这个时代最伟大的建筑!
The greatest erection on the planet!
这个星球上最伟大的建筑!
- Hold this. - Of course.
拿着这个.没问题.
For the Herald, Your Grace. I understand you'll be making an important announcement tonight.
据通报说,阁下.你将在今天晚上公告一个重要的通告.
Good afternoon, ladies. Please, excuse me, please.
下午好,女士们.对不起,让一让,对不起.下午好.
- And the Perrier-Jouet should be chilled. You understand? Chilled. Yes, sir.
Perrier-Jouet应该被冷冻起来,明白了吗?冷冻起来.-明白,先生.
Leopold!Leopold,你到那儿去了?
Leopold! Leopold, where have you been?
Leopold！Leopold!
Otis,我需要一个解释!已经5点半了!他甚至还没有打扮好!
Otis, I demand explication! It's half past 5:00! He's not even dressed!
他马上就好,我的主人.我向你保证.我不是要他马上就好.我是要他光彩照人!
- He'll be ready, my lord. I assure you. - I don't want him ready. I want him resplendent!
Ah, Miss Blaine.
哈,Blaine小姐.
你跳舞就像是......就像是一群小牛.
You dance like a... like a herd of cattle.
You are a rare woman who lights up a room simply by leaving it.
你是少有的那种女人她点亮房间然后只是简单的离去.
Might you be rich, Miss Blaine? You see..
可能会富裕,Blaine小姐?你瞧,
我是第三公爵我们两个在皇室的一点小秘密是
...whilst I am the third Duke the little secret of those of us in the Royal Court...
...apart from our general uselessness is our massive indebtedness.
除了无用的求婚外是受到最大的恩惠.
这就是你最大的不幸了Leopold
It's always been your misfortune, Leopold...
如此完全的自娱自乐用你自己讲出来的话.
...that you so thoroughly amuse yourself with the sound of your own voice.
在我乏味的生活中
In a life as stagnant as mine..
我能够始终的自娱自乐真是一种让人惊叹的变化.
...that I can amuse myself at all is an evolutionary marvel.
Hmm.请不要摸那个东西.你谈到的那个设备.
- Please don't touch that.  The device you were jabbering about.
把牧师带到钟楼的那个设备.
To take priests to the bell tower.
To take anyone, Uncle, to the floor they so desire.
能带任何人,叔父...到他们想到的那一层.
Buildings continue to climb. Soon they will outstrip the stamina of our legs.
建筑物在不停地升高.不久它们就会超出我们小腿能承受的高度.
你在说一种进步和发明.
You speak of progress and invention.
现在我叫你下楼这才是现实.
Yet what I offer you downstairs is reality.
找个老婆,结婚.
Take a wife. Marry.
结婚...
Marriage...
结婚是永恒爱情的一种诺言.
...marriage is the promise of eternal love.
As a man of honor, I can not promise eternally what I have never felt momentarily.
作为一个男人,我不能为永恒许下诺言我从来没有感觉到是短暂的
出生在一个特权阶层,却感到无比的羞耻.那就是你的悲剧所在.
Born into privilege, yet perversely ashamed of it. That is your tragedy.
上帝啊,如果我的兄弟还在能够看到你这样,他会心碎的.
My God! If my brother could only see you, he'll be heartbroken.
你不像是个公爵!当然,我不是.
- You are no duke! - Of course I'm not.
君主政治已经死了,我的叔父.我们只是遗迹,这就是现实.
The monarchy is dead, Uncle. We are relics. That is reality.
The new Royals are men of accomplishment. Men like Roebling, with his bridge..
那些真正的新贵应该是..作出成绩的人们.象Roebling和他建的桥,
...Edison, with his lamp, Diesel, Bell, Westinghouse...
爱迪生和他的灯发动机,闹钟, Westinghouse...
Those men made themselves from nothing!
这些人从一无所有做起!
你,从另方面看,生下来就拥有了一切从拥有一切开始,直到一无所有
You, on the other hand, were born with everything and from it, fashioned nothing.
As of tonight, I wash my hands of you.
从今晚开始,我再也不管你了.
好好看一下你的舞伴名单, Leopold.
Take a good look at your dance card, Leopold.
A wealthy bride is your only surety.
一个有钱的新娘才是你唯一的保证.
Your Grace, may I present Miss Tree of the Trees of Schenectady, sir.
阁下,请允许我为你介绍Tree小姐Schenectady家族的tree小姐,先生
Miss Tree?
Tree小姐?
It's an honor to be making your royal acquaintance, Your Highness.
非常的荣幸和你相识,阁下.
Shall we?
可以吗?
I've never been to England... but...
我从未去过英格兰...但...
Father's teeth were made there.
我父亲小时候去过那里
你父亲相当有钱是吧？
He's quite rich, your father?
Oh, yes..
额，是啊..
许多的梦,都是没有价值的.
Many dreams, all useless.
你是谁?
Who are you?
不,不,不.
No, no, no.
好的, ...请,等等, 别..我不想伤害你.
Please, wait, no. I don't want to harm you. Stop! Please!
先生，等一下
Sir, wait!
Please stop! Please!
站住! 请!
等等,先生!站住，Leopold
Stop! Leopold!
Pardon me. Pardon me.
原谅我.原谅我.
Go! Go!
走! 走!
站住,请等等先生!
Stop, sir! Please!
哦,我的天哪.
Oh, my God.
别!
No!
放开!
Let go!
Just let go. It's okay!
放开.没事的!
你不会明白的!放开!
You don't understand! Let go!
哦!我不想伤害你!放开!
- Oh!  I don't want to hurt you! Let go!
What?
什么？
- I'm sorry.  Well, you should be.
对不起。你一定会
It's just that...
只是…
如果有人敢那样做，就能得到你这样的女孩
if a guy like that can get a girl like you, what's left for a guy like me?
A guy like that can get a girl like me.
那样的男人能得到我
But a girl like me will never love him.
但我这样的女孩不会爱上他
你是说你爱我?
Are you saying you love me?
It's possible.
可能的
Turn it up higher.
高潮了
还有，高潮了
Some more, turn it up higher.
I've never felt so happy.
我从没这么高兴过
That's right, you can just leave it blank, Ok?
对的，如果你不晓得怎样写你可以不填，好吗?
这正是你真实的感受，对吗?
It's really just about what you're feeling. All right?
Guy in the windbreaker right there.
穿防风上衣的男子在那边
Two ladies right in front of him.
两位女士在他前面
Hey.
So how did you think it went?
你觉得怎么样？
我想，也就中场60分钟
Well, if I had to guess, mid 60's.
他们为什么不喜欢看?
Why don't they love it?
She's not likeable.  She's right.
她不可爱。-她很好
Absolutely. I can do some trims where she sleeps with her boss.
绝对好。有些整理的地方 她和她的老板睡觉
剪掉那些部分。-抱歉
- Cut that whole section.  Excuse me?
Excuse me. What are you talking about?
-抱歉，你们在讨论什么?
- The movie, Richard, your movie?  I'm aware of that.
讨论电影，里查，你拍的电影。我知道
我想说
I want to say something.
I think Julie is likeable. Very likeable in this picture.
我想朱丽很可爱．.．在这画面很可爱
And real.
也很真实
请问，你一生中…从来没有犯错吗?
What, excuse me, you've never made a mistake in your life?
You have no flaws? You never slept with the wrong guy?
没有缺陷吗?没有和睡错人吗?
I'm not the protagonist in a major motion picture.
我不是动作画面的主角
我来告诉你，你们吸取了美国电影的糟粕
Let me tell you something, you people, you are sucking the life out of American cinema.
Richard, come on.
理查德,别
It's a comedy. But it's also a drama. It can be about something.
这是喜剧,但是同时也是连续剧，这有其他意外的东西!
"You are sucking the life out of American cinema."
你们吸取了美国电影的糟粕
吸取了美国电影的糟粕？
"You are sucking the life out of American cinema"?
不认为他带有这样的思想吗?什么？
- Maybe he's got a point, though? - What?
好吧
Well...
Don't you ever think that what we do is a bit... crass?
你不认为我们所做的有点太愚钝，冷酷了吗？
We find out what regular people think and we pass on their wisdom.
我们发现正常人所想的我们是传递着他们的智慧
那就是我们所做的。那是愚钝?冷酷吗?我不这样认为
That's what we do. Is that crass? Is that cold? I don't think so.
我们就像是花生酱一样温柔，我们制作的是像谷物一样的脆弱的
We make peanut butter creamier. We make cereal crunchier.
Sit-coms funnier. Boring movies shorter.
连续剧。
我们让史马克把种籽从果酱里分离出来
We made Smuckers get the seeds out of their jam.
We did that. If you ask me, we're heroes.
我们就这样做的，如果你要问我，我会说我们是英雄
It goes with the territory every once in a while some pompous jerk...
只是把这个领域每个方面
sticks his head out of his cave and says...
把他脑子里的一些华而不实的东西抛弃而且说
"Hey, I like seeds in my jam. Without seeds it's just jelly."
“嘿，我喜欢在果酱里有种子的”“没有种子那就成了果冻了”
"You people are sucking the life out of my condiments."
“你们那就不符合我的调味品”
你知道我对他说了什么吗?这就是我对他说的，戴思
I say to him... this is what I say to him, Darcy...
You, baby, are one percent of one percent.
你是百分之一中的百分之一
你的意见是你不切题的
Your opinion is irrelevant.
I went out with a visionary like you for four years.
我像这样已经幻想4年
And I had to pay his rent?!
我并且必须给他付租金
Because he couldn't stoop down and get a job, like the rest of us?
因为他不能像我们一样找到工作?
这和史超活无关。是这样!
- This is not about Stuart. Yes it is!
It is about Stuart. It's about anybody who can't face up to reality.
这和史超活有关。这和任何不能面对事实的人都有关
I don't care if it's crass. Give me the number. Give me the bottom line.
我不在乎是否愚钝，给我韵律，给我底线…
直接给我事实，而不是把我当成猎人
Give me the truthstraight up, no chaser.
Bart!
巴特!(狗名)
别动!
Quiet!
哦,我的天那.
Oh my God!
We must remember, Bart...
一定要记着,巴特
...that sometimes, it is okay to color outside the lines.
有些时候一定要站线上的外面.
喂?║我的掌上电脑在你那儿吗?.
- Hello? - My Palm Pilot. You still have it.
Kate,现在是早晨1点钟了.
Kate, it's 1:00 in the morning.
很显然你还醒着在,你又在干什么坏勾当?
And clearly you're awake, so what is the infraction?
听着,Kate,我不知道你的掌上电脑那儿.
Look, Kate, I don't know where your Palm Pilot is.
And I can't do this right now. Not now. I'm expecting a call.
我现在也没法给你找.我在等一个电话.
Oh, Bart. Oh, I'm sorry, baby.
哦,巴特.哦,对不起,宝贝.
她不是个快乐的人.
She is not a happy person.
Goddamn it!
该死!
- You know what, Stuart?You know what? I'm... - Kate...
你知道吗,斯图亚特?你知道吗? 我...Kate...
别.... 我这儿有个人, 好吗?
Please. I've got somebody here, okay?
我知道,我看见她了.
I know. I saw her.
- No, you didn't.  Yes, I did!
没有,你没看见.是,我看见了!
It's a him, if that's any kind of consolation to you.
是个男的, 如果这样可以给你一点安慰.
So, look, now that you know I'm not getting laid, just go to bed, okay?
听着,你现在知道了我没有给你撒谎,上床睡觉吧,好吗?
Nuh-uh, don't. Do not hang up on me, Stuart. Don't do that.
别,别,别挂掉我的电话,斯图亚特.别那样做.
Kate,别这样.
Kate, please.
I beg of you. Something big is happening.
我求你了,有大事发生了.
Something...
事情
关系到我的一生...
...that validates my entire life.
"Something that validates your entire life.  What could that possibly be?
事情也关系到你的一生...可能会是什么事情?
- Are you sitting down? - Yes.
你是坐着的吗?是.
-不,你没有.-是,我坐着.
- No, you're not.  Yes, I am.
- No, you're not.  Ye...
不,你没有.是...
Okay.
好吧.
I found it.
我找到了.
- What did you find? - A portal.
你找到什么了?入口.
A crack in the fabric of time.
时间构造的入口.
就在东河的上面,Kate就是我曾经说过可能是入口的那儿.
It was over the East River, Kate, just where I said it would be.
- You found the portal? A portal into April 28th, 1876.
你找到入口了?一个到1876年4月28日的入口.
I jumped off the Brooklyn Bridge...
今天我从布鲁克林大桥跳入
然后到1876 年去散了一会儿步.
...and took a walk in 1876 today.
I followed my great, great grandpa, around old New York.
我跟随着Albany(纽约州府)的公爵,环绕了旧纽约州一周.
- Are you listening? Avidly.
你在听吗?非常急切.
现在事情有了突变Kate.这儿来了个捣蛋鬼.
This here's the twist, Kate. Here's the kicker.
什么捣蛋鬼?
What's the kicker?
He followed me home.
他跟我回到家了.
你爷爷的爷爷...是的
- Your great-great grandfather...  Yes.
- Viscount of Buffalo.  No, he's not a viscount...
(水牛城)的公爵...
- The Duke of Buffalo...  No, the Duke of Albany.
不,是Albany(纽约州府)的公爵.
...公爵跟你回家了穿过时间的裂缝.他是个杰出的工程师.
- Albany followed you home through a crack in time.  He's a brilliant engineer.
He patented the counterweight pulley. He invented the elevator, for Christ's sake.
他获得了平衡力滑车的专利.他发明了电梯.
You know what, Stuart? You know what? I'm not your girlfriend anymore.
你知道吗,斯图亚特?你知道吗?我再也不是你的女朋友了.
I haven't been for a whole month now.
我已经有一个多月不再是了.
- You can tell me the truth.   I am telling you the truth, Kate.
你可以告诉我实情是什么.我正在告诉你实情,Kate.
你可以告诉我你...到时代广场穿着女士衣服走了一圈.我不在乎.
You can tell me you went and picked up a transvestite in Times Square. I don't care.
知道吗,Kate?就是这一点.就是这一点,核心所在.我们两个分手的原因
You know what, Kate?║This is it, right here. This is it, in a nutshell. Our downfall.
You never... not once... believed in me.
你从来没有,哪怕是一次--相信过我.
Oh, I did, Stuart. I did, for four years. And I got burnt.
哦,我相信过,斯图亚特.我相信了四年.║终于看清了.
Okay, you want to know who he is? I'll tell you who he is.
好了,你想知道他是谁?我告诉你他是谁.
He is a hacker. High end. English.I know him from Columbia.
他是个黑客.英国人.我在哥伦比亚大学认识的.
He's in town for the Mac Expo at the Javits.
他现在在这个城市做苹果电脑出口.
We went out, got a little sloppy on Guinness and he passed out on my couch.
我们一块儿出去喝了点?啤酒然后他脑袋发昏睡在我的沙发上.
那就是真相?Mm-hmm. 那就是真相.好了吗?你现在高兴了?
- And that's the truth? - Mm-hmm. That's the truth. Okay? Are you happy now?
Is that plausible enough for you and your little focus group?
那样更合乎情理吗?对你或者对你那一小群朋友来讲?
You know what, Stuart?
知道吗,斯图亚特?
我把我最好的年华花在你身上了.
I blew my best years on you.
Those were your best?
那就是你最好的?
Look...
听着...
对不起.
I'm sorry.
I have to go. You'll get your Pilot in the morning.
我得挂了.你早晨会拿到你的掌上电脑的.
Orange alert.
橘色警告.
哦!Otis(人名)!Otis!
What is it?
Bart! No!
巴特,别闹!
Bart, stop!
It's okay.
没事了
- You? It's okay.
你？-别激动.
- Where am I?  Well, um, there's not an easy explanation for that.
-我在什么地方?哦.um,真是不容易给你解释这个问题.
如果你是想要赎金的话,我的叔父会付钱给你的.也许,除了我死亡以外
If it's a ransom you seek, my uncle won't pay a cent. Except, perhaps, for my demise.
No. no. You're not being kidnapped. Bart, quiet!
不,不,你没有被绑架.巴特,安静!
I can scarcely see, thanks to your spray.
由于你那个喷雾器我几乎什么都看不到.
My eyes feel like Steak au Poivre. So I ask you again, where the hell am I?
我的眼睛就像是.....糊满了洋芋泥.所以我再问你一次,我在该死的什么地方?!
As far as I'm concerned...
就如我所担心的,
you might be Jack the Ripper!
你也许是个变态杀手!
那你是要我相信我被留在了未来?还没有到来的时间中?
And you would have me believe that I'm being detained at present in the hereafter? The time to come?
Yes. Bart, quiet! He needs a walk.
是的.巴特,安静!他需要散散步.
And you would have me believe that you you are my progeny.
哦,那你还需要....让我相信你是我的后裔
一个我还没谱的婚姻的产物？
A product of a marriage unmade.
Yes.
是的
Oh! And you would have me believe that you have found a crack in time.
哦！你还要我相信你发现了一个时间裂缝。
你,在所有的人中是最应该相信的.我是说,你是一个科学家.你发明了电梯.
You, of all people, should understand. I mean, you're a scientist. You invented the elevator.
What is an elevator? What the hell are you talk... Where the hell am I?!
电梯是什么东西?你到底在讲什么啊...我究竟在该死的什么地方?!
I told you... you haven't actually gone anywhere. You're still in New York.
我告诉你...你实际上那儿都没有去.你还在纽约.
先生,这儿不是纽约!
That, sir, is not New York!
I'm afraid it is.
我恐怕这儿就是.
- No, Kate.  Hello. Hello there. What's your name?
别Kate.嗨,嗨,你.你叫什么名字?
-Leopold.
Leopold.
Tell me something. I'm having trouble with my G-5.
-请教 一个问题.我遇到了一点麻烦我用我的G-5的时候.
How much RAM do I need to properly run OS 9.6?
我需要多大的记忆体正确来运行OS 9.6?
Clearly, the Mac Expo is out.
很显然.苹果机专家走了.
So you must be a man out of time? Or Sergeant Pepper?
那你肯定是...时间以外的来人?或者是个海军陆战队战士?
-知道吗?实际上我们可以保留一点隐私.斯图亚特,我要要我的掌上电脑.
- You know what? Actually, we could use a little privacy. Stuart, I want my Palm Pilot.
我不是....我是认真的.晚点吧,Kate.我只是要我的掌上电脑,斯图亚特!
- I'm not... I'm serious. Maybe later on, Kate. I just want my Palm Pilot, Stuart!
- No. No. Hey, give me my Palm Pilot!║Give it to me.
不,不.嗨,把我的掌上电脑还给我!还给我.
This is madness.
简直是疯了
This is madness. Who was that? I feel as if I've seen her...
简直是疯了.她是谁?-我觉得像是我以前见过她...
Women have changed since your time, Leo. They've become dangerous.
女人从你那个时代开始已经发生变化了,Leo.她们开始变得更加危险了.
It's on the landing!
我给你抛下来了!
你说这不是绑架.你说这不会有危险.
You say this is no kidnapping. You say you mean no harm.
Then why is it, sir, you will not unlock the door?
那为什么,先生,把门窗关上?
I'm sorry, okay? I'm sorry about her. I'm...
对不起,好吧?对不起主要是对她.....
听着, 出于对你的尊重我不能让你就这样在外面自由自在的行走,行吗?
Look, with all due respect I can't let you just go running around free out there, okay?
This is New York City. It's not such a safe place anymore.
这是纽约城.这儿再也不是一个安全的城市了.
Look at you. You look like some sort of psychotic escapee from a Renaissance faire.
你看你自己.就像是一个从文艺复兴时期精神病院跑出来的病人.
I understand you have some anxiety but you have to trust me.
我知道你肯定感觉到有点焦虑但是你一定要相信我.
我肯定把你送回家,好吗?
I'm going to get you home, okay?
I promise.
我保证.
Bart!
巴特!
The portal opens up again next week. Monday.
入口下个星期一还会打开.
I know that, because it was my back-up in case I didn't make it last night.
我知道,因为我以防万一做了准备我昨夜还没有做完我的工作.
这是一个回圈,知道吗?就像是...日全蚀.
It's on a cycle, you know? Kind of like, uh... total eclipse.
每20年来一次.你明白了吗?
Once every 20 years. You understand?
一般来讲,我什么都明白.自从我遇到你以后,什么都不知道了.
Generally, I understand everything. Since I've met you, nothing.
I can only assume I'm in a nightmare brought on by agita, or else I am dead.
我只能假设自己在一场梦魇之中带来的这些焦虑或者我已经死了.
You're not dead. Come here. Sit down. Here.
你还没有死.过来,坐下.这儿.
Want some milk in yours?
想要加点牛奶吗?
巴特,我能不能..........
Bart, can I just have...
Sorry. He's really got to go out.
对不起,它确实是需要外出散步了.瞧这些.
I'll be honored if you took a look at those.
嗯...你把这些东西看看我会很高兴的.
嗯,我回来后可以给你解释这一切.它一定要出去了要不它就会在这儿丢炸弹(拉屎)了.
Um, I'll explain everything when I get back. He's got to go out or he's going to drop a bomb in there.
Come on. Let's go.
来吧,我们走吧.
Back in five.
五分钟后回来.
One quick trip to Spectra, Bart...
来一个短的光际旅行,巴特
你和我就将会赢得诺贝尔桂冠
...and you and I will be Nobel Laureates.
Come on, Bart.
过来，巴特.
嗨，我们走.
Hey, let's go.
-过来.我们走!
Come on. Let's go.
Oh, Jesus!
噢!
噢,天哪!
Oh, God.
Good boy, Bart!
好孩子,巴特!
Stay!
坚持住!
Stay, Bart! Stay!
坚持住,巴特!
Oh, Bart, please stay!
坚持住!噢,巴特,请坚持住!
Stuart you forgot the pointy thing!
斯图亚特你忘了把掌上电脑的笔给我!
Stuart...
斯图亚.....
Look, this is not complex. He gave me the Palm Pilot║but he forgot the pointy thing.
听着，这并不复杂.他把掌上电脑还给我但是忘了把笔给我.
- I've been warned about you. Oh. Really?
我要警告你.噢，是吗?
And what, pray tell, did the great disappointment say?
天知道你要说些什么让人失望的话?
你刚才很危险,尽管你自己不觉得.噢，是吗?
- That you were dangerous, though you hardly look it.  Oh, really?
A lady in trousers isn't dangerous, merely plain.
-一个穿着裤子的女士不危险只是简朴.
我猜想你是个职业妇女是，搞市场研究.
- I take it you're a career woman.  Yeah, market research.
Mm. Fine avocation for women, research.
对妇女来讲是个很好的职业，研究.
Perfect for the feminine mind.
对女士的智力来讲非常好.
Huh.你在旅行,Lionel.
You're a trip, Lionel.
I myself once courted a librarian in Sussex.
我曾经向Sussex（苏赛克斯郡）的一个图书管理员求婚
Good for you.
喔.那很好啊.啊!
我必须坦白我觉得我们在先前的那一个场合见过.
I must confess I feel as though we've met on a previous occasion.
Well, Lionel, seeing as I've never met a single friend of Stuart's.
喔,Lionel,看起来..我从来没有见过斯图亚特的其他朋友--
I'm not even sure he's ever had any. I really don't see how that's possible.
我甚至觉得他是否有其他朋友--我真的不明白怎么会有那种可能.
噢，天哪，巴特!
Oh, man! Bart!
He just made Lake Erie out there. You just can't toss a dog out into the hall like that.
它刚在那儿撒了泡尿.你不能把狗象那样扔在巷道里.
- You can't do that. I assure you, I did not.
你不能那样做.我保证，我没有.
我们走吧.说什么?
- Let's go. I beg your pardon?
Come on. Let's go!
走吧.我们走!
Bart...
巴特...
Look, pal, I don't care how many elevators you got. This one's in my building.
听着，伙计,我不在乎你要修多少电梯.在这幢楼的电梯.
Hang-hang on a second.
挂在那儿不动了.
电梯的事情实在对不起，kate小姐.我马上打电话叫人来修.
Sorry about the elevator, Miss Kate. I've got them on the phone right now.
Hey, Gracy. This is Lionel, Stuart's friend.
咳y,Gracy.这是Lionel,斯图亚特的朋友.
How do you do?
你好吗?
Ten minutes? I need someone here right now.
十分钟?我要人马上就过来修.
- Watch it, man.  I beg your pardon.
-你小心点儿,伙计.实在对不起.
Hey, what are you doing?
咳，你在干什么?
You need to be going that way. There's an electron...
你应该朝那个方向走.那儿有一个电子.....
喂?喂? 那儿有一个电子商店.喂?
Hello? Hello? There's an electronics store. Hello?
I'm sorry, miss.
对不起，小姐.
There's a patch of grass across the street. Take him there. He'll do his business.
街那边有一个草坪.把它带到那儿，它自己会在那儿方便的.
请把这个交给斯图亚特吧?这是他的有线电视帐单.
Can you give this to Stuart, please? It's his cable bill.
They haul our furniture and cradle our children but this morning, from the Battery to the Bronx...
他们搬走我们的家具把婴儿放入摇篮今天早晨在纽约布朗克斯区的
elevators have mysteriously...
电梯不可思议的..........
So sorry.
真是对不起.
- I do beg your pardon.  Stupid!
我真的请你原谅.笨蛋
I beg your pardon.
我请你原谅.
你不打算把它弄走吗?
Are you going to remove that?
I beg your pardon?
对不起?
Pick it up and put it in the trash.
把它捡起来扔到垃圾桶去.
Absolutely not.
决不.
Maybe you don't understand. It's against the law to leave it there.
看来你没有听明白.把它留在这儿是违法的.
Are you suggesting, madam, there exists a law..
你的意思是，女士，有这样一个法律
可以强制一个绅士把狗粪弄走吗?
...compelling gentlemen to lay hold of canine bowel movements?
I'm suggesting you pick the poop up and throw it away now.
我建议现在你把狗粪弄走把它扔到垃圾筒去.
I refuse. Respectfully.
我拒绝. （恭敬的）.
那好吧.你叫什么名字，花痴?
All right. What's your name, fancy pants?
Leopold...Leopold...
Alexis Elija Walker..Alexis Elija Walker...
Thomas Garret Mountbatten（姓名）.
...Thomas Garrett Mountbatten.
All right, Stuart.
好了，斯图亚特.
Have a nice day.
祝你愉快.
我很感谢你给我说的这些好话，但是J.J.还没有从伦敦回来.
I appreciate you putting in a good word for me but J.J.'s not back from London.
- Right. Bye. What's with the elevators? - It's happening everywhere.
好的，再见.电梯怎么了?到处都在发生.
Darci（名字）.
Darci.
Last page.
最后一页.
Sorry.
对不起.
Did everyone live happily ever after?
最后是否都过得很快乐?
他在岛上等并且他失去了一只腿.
He lost his leg to gangrene  waiting for her on the island.
- But they're together now.  Wonderful.
但最后他们终于在一起了.太精彩了.
- Oh, look, you got your Palm Pilot back.  A nightmare.
喔，瞧，你把你的掌上电脑拿回来了.一场梦魇.
Okay, so who do I owe?
好了，我欠下些什么要做的?
Okay, Bobby at Hasbro. Reeves at Crunch.
好吧，Bobby在Hasbro等你.
And the finals came in for "Love for Sale." The call with the studio's at 4:00.
摄影棚在4点有个电话.
有关黄油销售的会议在15分钟后在会议室召开.
The margarine thing's in 15 in the conference room.
J.J. wants to talk to you before that. Oh, and one more thing.
在这些事情之前J.J.有话要给你讲.对了，还有一件事.
I remember that you told me to start thinking ahead...
我记得你告诉我做事要提前考虑
所以我告诉你你的兄弟明天
...so I know your brother's getting back..
- ...from his retreat tomorrow and if you want something in the fridge... - Darci...
从夏令营回来了另外你是否需要从冰箱中拿点..-Darci..什么?
Can you tell me why I'm upset right now?
你能告诉我为什么现在我很沮丧吗?
那是因为,.....
Because, uh...
J.J. called this morning. That is why I have a cell phone. So you can call me...
J.J.早晨给我打了电话.这就是我为什么会有个手机.因此你可以先打电话给我..
Kate, Kate, he didn't call. He just popped his head in here and spoke two sentences.
Kate, Kate,他没有打到这儿他只是在这儿晃了一下讲了几句话.
那他回来了?
So he's back?
Margo说他将要做一个重大声明关于下周的合并.
Margo says he's going to make a big announcement about the merger next week.
Margo? What does she know? How does she know anything about anything?
Margo?她知道些什么?她怎么会知道这些事那些事?
喔，好了，
Oh. All right.
So he popped his head in here. All right, so you have to tell me exactly what he said, Darci.
那他来过这儿了？.好的，那你告诉我他到底讲了些什么，
你从头开始讲给我听...
You have to start at the beginning and tell me...
He said, "Tell Kate I'm going to sit in on Farmer's Bounty."
他说, "告诉Kate我将代理农场产品"
J.J...J.J.
- Good morning, Kate.  Good morning.
早晨好, Kate.早晨好.
我在办公室见你.
I'll see you in there.
我的上帝,它还立在那儿.
Good Lord, it still stands.
The world has changed all around it but Roebling's erection still stands!
它周围的世界已经变了但是它却还在那儿立着!
瞧，我的朋友，这是个奇迹.
That, my friend, is a miracle.
- What?  It's a miracle, man!
什么?这是个奇迹，伙计!
It's a bridge.
这是个桥.
Tell me when did they adapt it for steam engines?
告诉我...是什么时候让它适应蒸气机的?
The fire brigade.
消防队.
I don't know how it happened. I found him in a shaft.
我不知道这是怎样发生的.我在电梯井里找到他.
斯图亚特!
Stuart!
Leopold, what are you doing out here?
Leopold,你在这儿干什么?
Get back inside!
快回去，进里面去!
They're taking him to Goodman Memorial.
他们把他送到好主人纪念馆去(地名?医院?).
Fresh creamery butter.
新鲜的精炼黄油.
Is there anything more comforting?
还有什么令人鼓舞的事情?
There is and I know you will agree when you try Farmer's Bounty...
有我知道你们一定会赞同当你们在试用农场产品的时候
...with the essence of real butter in every bite.
在你咬每一口的时候都会感受到黄油的清香.
Your first choice. However, 45% of our demo circled "shifty"...
你的第一选择.不管怎样,45%的人都觉得
他的语调非常的令人难受.这个不行.
...as his key descriptor. Not good.
This is what I say. Everybody should be trying Farmer's Bounty..
这就是我为什么说.每个人都应该试试农场产品
...with the real, rich, creamy taste of real butter.
有着真正的,浓浓的奶油香味的黄油.
Try it, and you will be losing pounds. Poof! Boom! Voila!
试试吧,你的体重会随之减轻 oof! Boom! Voila(表示惊叹的语气词)!
Your second choice. Unfortunately, the group found him obnoxious, abrasive..
你的第二选择.不幸的是,观众发现他表情让人讨厌
有72%的人觉得他让人毛骨悚然.
...and a whopping 72% found him just plain creepy.
The spot rolls out in four days. We have to...
广告在四天内就将播出我们必须.....
The product is shipping. What the hell am I supposed to do?
我到底该怎么做才行啊?
我们只有明天再做一个片断.
We have to do another session. Tomorrow.
I had my assistant book the response room at National so we can decide then and there.
我的助手已经预定了答复的时间和地点在电视台，所以我们可以在那儿给他们答复
Kate,你没事吧?没事吧?
- Kate, are you all right?  You okay?
我没事.天,Kate,我要一杯咖啡.
- I'm fine. Geez, Kate, I'll ask for a decaf.
Monica, I need you to call Barney's. I need a white blouse, size small...
Monica,我要你给巴尼打个电话.我要一件短上衣,小号的
...in Kate's office by lunch.
午饭的时候送到kate的办公室.
-哦,安逸.
Oh, dear.
Hi, you've reached Stuart. Please leave a message.
嗨,你接通了斯图亚特的电话.请你留下消息.
Leopold? Leopold, look, don't be frightened. This is Stuart, okay?
Leopold? Leopold,听着,别害怕.我是斯图亚特,明白吗?
这就是贝尔可以讲话的电报?
Is it Bell's talking telegraph?
- I saw a prototype at last year's faire.  I need you to pick up the handset, Leo.
我去年看到过他的原型机.我要你把话机的听筒拿起来,Leo.
You pick up the green handset, because I need to talk to you...
把那个绿色的听筒拿起来,我有话要给你讲...
Are-are you there? Hello?
你听到了吗?-喂?
Leopold, thank God. Listen, they're taking me to X Rays.
-Leopold,谢天谢地.听着,他们要把我送去做x光透视.
Everything's going to be fine but you have to stay in the apartment, do you understand me?
不会有什么事情的但是你必须就待在房子里明白了吗?
哦,斯图亚特,我今天看到大桥了.
Oh, Stuart, I saw Roebling's bridge today.
- I saw it... complete.  Yes, yes, but listen to me.
我看到了... 清清楚楚的.知道,知道,你听我讲.
You can't go out again. You have to stay in the apartment.
你不能再出去了.你一定要待在房子里.
待在房子里?待好久?Leo,我晚上就回来.
- Stay in the apartment? For how long? - Leo, I'll be back tonight. I promise.
No more field trips.
我保证,再也不会有这种考察旅行了.
Would you...
你是否...
喂... 喂?斯图亚特?
Hel... hello? Stuart?
Hello?
喂?
Blast!
该死!
喂.
Hello.
你是谁?
Who are you?
Hector(名字)我妈妈星期三工作到很晚
Hector. My mom works late on Wednesdays...
...so I watch TV with Stuart.
所以我就到斯图亚特这儿看电视.
Want some Pirate's Booty?
要不要点薯片?
Excuse me, J.J., I wanted to thank you for the shirt. That was very nice.
对不起J.J.,我来谢谢你给的上衣.非常好看.
进来,进来.
Come in, come in.
Yeah. Uh-huh.
是,啊哈.
绝对是.
Absolutely.
哦,好的,好的.是,她就在这儿.我会告诉她的.
Oh, good, good. Yeah, she's here right now. I'll tell her.
Okay... okay. Bye.
好的... 好的.再见.
Sit down.
坐下.
That was Barry. He was thrilled with your work at the screening last night.
是Barry(名字)来的电话.他对你昨天晚上在摄影棚的拍摄感到非常激动.
Oh, good. Good.
哦,好,好
你是女人中少有的那一种,Kate.
You're a rarity among women, Kate.
I'm sorry?
对不起?
You don't cling to illusion. You don't get...
你不靠想像办事.你也不
受情绪的影响.
...caught up in emotion.
You don't do pretty.
你也不打扮.
I don't?
我不?
你倾向个男人.你更像个男人.
You skew male. You're like a man.
A man who understands women their desires, their needs.
一个了解女人的男人--她们的愿望,需要.
You understand them but you're not really one of them.
你了解她们但你不是她们中的一员.
你不会介意我的这种直率吧?不,不会的.
- You don't mind my being frank, do you? - No. I don't. No.
Edamame?
来点乳酪?
Kate?
但是有一天,他放下了海盗旗-斯图?
- But one day, he lowered the Jolly Roger... - Stu?
...and set sail in search another kind of treasure.
-开始出航去寻找另外一种宝藏.
不是金钱,不是珠宝,不是黄金...而是新娘.
Not money, not jewels, not gold... but a bride.
Despite his being a ruffian of the brine fearless in his plunder...
不管浓浓的海水对他进行怎样的侵蚀
...and merciless with the sword the Pirate King was also lonely.
还有刀剑对他的攻击海海盗王仍然觉得孤独.
You see, he had never met a lady.
明白吗,他从来没有见过一个女士.
他从来没有见过姑娘?
He never met a girl?
No. Not a girl, not a lady, not even his own mother.
不,不仅是姑娘l, 女士,甚至是他自己的母亲.
So what happened?
-那最后发生了什么?
-就像所有的喜剧一样最滑稽的事情是...
As with all comedies the most ridiculous thing imaginable...
the Pirate King fell in love with the major general's daughter.
海盗王爱上了陆军少将的女儿.
I had the good fortune to see the premiere last month at the Fifth Avenue Theatre.
上个月正好我有机会看了首映式在第五大道的剧院.
从什么时候起剧院搬到第五大道了?
Since when is Penzance at the Fifth?
Is it your habit, sir to simply enter a conversation without introduction?
这就是你的习惯吗?先生?不加一点介绍就直接加入到别人的对话中?
Whoa, you are deep in it.
哇,你刚才太沉迷了.
It's cool. I'm an actor, too. I'm Charlie. I live downstairs.
太好了,我也是个演员.我是查理.住在楼下.
Kate McKay, senior vice president.
Kate McKay,(名字)副总裁.
Darci, it hasn't happened.
Darci,还没有开始啊.
他刚才做的只是在你面前挂个胡萝卜.直到他作出最后的决定
All he did was dangle a carrot. Until he makes a decision..
- ...the pressure's doubled.  When's he going to make a decision?
现在是双倍的压力.他什么时候会作决定?
我们明天中午午餐的时候..进行一次更亲密的讨论.
We're having dinner tomorrow to discuss it further at Commune.
- Kate?  Yeah.
-Kate?-是.
-斯图亚特的电话在一线上-不!
- I have Stuart on the line.  No!
-他说他  不！
- He says he's...  No!
在医院里.
...in the hospital.
Leopold is just sitting alone in my apartment right now. God knows what could happen to him.
Leopold现在一个人在我的公寓里.天知道在他身上会发生些什么事情.
Do you know he got outside today?
你知道他今天到外面去了吗?
Of course he did... I made him walk your dog.
当然知道--我让他带你的狗出去溜溜.
What?
什么?
No, Kate, you can't do that! He can't go outside!
别,Kate,你不能那样做!他不能到外面去!
天哪,我的上帝,Kate.他是从1876年来的, Kate.
Jesus Christ, Kate. He's from 1876, Kate.
他不了解我们这个社会.如果在他身上发生什么事情的话
He doesn't know our customs. If something were to happen to him it could be catastrophic.
His mere presents has already caused an occlusion.
-他唯一的去咯已经关闭
Occlusion!
关闭
If he doesn't go back on Monday, I may cease to exist!
如果他星期一不回去，我也许就要消失
我是他的后代，Kate，上帝知道有多少这样的人
I'm his decedent, Kate, along with God knows how many other people.
如果他不能回到1876年4月28日
If he doesn't go back to April 28, 1876,
he doesn't get married, he doesn't have children, and you want to know what?
他就不能够结婚他就不会有小孩,你想知道会是什么样吗?
What happened with the elevators today, well that's going to seem like a walk in the park. - Stuart!
会对今天的电梯造成什么样的影响这就看起来像是在公园的一次散步.斯图亚特!
This is embarrassing. It's embarrassing now, all right?
这真是让人尴尬了.太让人尴尬了,行吗?
I'm sorry that you got hurt.
我很同情你的伤
But there happens to be a lot going on with me right now.
但是对我来说碰巧的事太多了
一定要有人看住他.
Someone has to keep an eye on him.
Stuart, he's a grown man.
斯图亚特,他是个成年人了.
He's a grown man. He's fine.
他是个成年人,他没事.
他可以照顾他自己.-不,等等,啊哈!║-我走了.
- He can take care of himself.  No. Wait. Aah!  I'm going.
Kate, please.
Kate,请别.
Just take this to Spectra, okay? Get it developed.
把这个带给Spectra, 好吗?继续开发一下.
你就会看到我告诉你的是真实的.告诉Manny这很重要.
You'll see... I'm telling the truth. Tell Manny it's important.
You want double prints?
你要我把它印两份吗?
That's not funny, Kate. This is not a joke.
这不好笑,Kate.这不是个笑话.
You need help, Stuart. You need help.
你需要帮助了,斯图亚特.你需要帮助了.
Charlie?
查理?
Hey, Kate!
嗨,Kate!
下来我要和你谈几分钟?
Can I see you downstairs for a minute?
I invited someone to dinner. He's up there all alone.
我邀请了人来吃晚饭.
Stuart's in the hospital. I didn't think you'll have such a problem...
他一个人在楼上.斯图亚特在医院里.我没有想到你有这样的问题...
不,你没有想到,查理.你没有想到.
No, you didn't think, Charlie. You didn't think.
You came home early, one day early from actor camp.
你这么早回家,从你那个夏令营回来.
Okay, it's not actor camp and yeah, I came home a day early, all right?
好了,那不是夏令营我就是回来早了一点罢了,行了吧?
不就是上楼...-弹了一会儿钢琴...
There was this tai chi broad who kept trying stick her fingers...
No, this is the point. You immediately march upstairs to my ex-boyfriend's apartment...
不,这不是我要说的.你回来就立刻上楼跑到我前男朋友的房间
然后又邀请他那个异想天开的男朋友...瞧,那就是关于这些.不是因为我上了楼.
- ...and you invite his freakish friend...  See, that's what it's about. It's not that I went up there.
主要是关于你的前男友...不,不是说斯图亚特.
- It's that it was your ex-boyfriend...  No, it's not about Stuart.
Greetings, Kate. Charles.
你好啊,Kate.查理.
Hey, Leo.
嗨,Leo.
表现好点.
Be nice.
那么,斯图亚特什么时候回来?几天,也许一周吧.
- So, when's Stuart getting back?  Couple days, maybe a week.
He promised me that he would return late this evening.
他向我保证最迟今天晚上就回来.
Well, maybe he will, Leopold. He's so big on keeping his promises...
瞧,也许他会,Leopold.他就是这么会许愿.
May I have the next course?
我可以要下一道菜吗?
There is no next course.
没有下一道菜了.
Where I come from the meal is the result of reflection and study.
哈.我来的那个地方食品都是烹饪研究的结果.
Menus are prepared in advance timed to perfection.
菜谱是在开饭之前早就准备妥当了.
It is said, without the culinary arts the crudeness of reality would be unbearable.
这就是说,没有经过厨师的精心烹饪现代的天然食品简直令人难以接受.
我们在McKay(kate)的房子里你只有说:
We had a saying in the McKay house:
"You shake and shake the ketchup bottle. None will come, and then a lot'll."
"你摇摇番茄酱的瓶子.就这样了."
- What is that? I beg your pardon?
你这是干吗?对不起(什么意思)?
你站起来干吗?
Why are you standing?
I'm accustomed to stand when a lady leaves the table.
我习惯站起来当一个女士离开桌子的时候.
Tell me, Charles when Stuart and your sister were engaged...
告诉我,查理你的姐姐什么时候和斯图亚特订婚的?
...did you happen to read his papers on the temporal universe?
你是否看过他的那些资料关于暂时的宇宙空间的那些?
I spent the morning perusing them, and must confess...
我花了一个早晨仔细看了,我不得不承认...
Stuart and I were never engaged. Not even close.
斯图亚特和我从来没有订过婚.没有那么近过.
我看过...
But I did read...
Thank you.
谢谢.
我看过那些资料不管如何,表示支持.
But I did read his papers however, to show support.
Is Stuart still trying to make a time machine?
斯图亚特还在试验..制造时间机器?
That's the beauty of it, he discovered no machine was necessary.
干得最漂亮的是--他发现...根本不需要时间机器.
All one had to do was to develop formula to forecast portals...
所有需要做的是去发现规律预报出入口在那儿--
在时间构造上的一个自然的视窗.
...natural windows in the fabric of time.
很显然,斯图亚特找到了一个利用现代的...
Apparently, Stuart located one utilizing modern...
Utilizing modern theories of weather prediction.
哈!利用现代的天气预报的理论.
What's a portal?
什么入口?
An opening which exists for but a moment.
一个在短时间内打开并存在的视窗.
This explains why one must jump through it from a height...
这就可以解释为什么他必须从很高的地方跳下--
以便达到一个很高的速度来完成.地心引力的速度,这需要很精确.真是太精彩了.
in order to achieve the required velocity. The speed of gravity, to be exact. It's quite brilliant.
You are so method. You don't even break for a second, do you? It's unbelievable!
你太文绉绉了.你简直不想停一下,是吗?真是不可思议!
Oh, stop it, please! No more! Stop, please? I beg you. I'm tired. Can you go away?
哦,请别说了!不要再说了,请别说了?我求你了,我累了.你该走了?
你走了好不好?你走了吧?
Can you just go away? Can you go away?
她喝醉了,Leo.哦,闭嘴,查理!
- She's drunk, Leo.  Oh, shut up, Charlie!
And you, can you go upstairs? Can you go away?
还有你,你上楼去行不行?你也走吧?
如果我在那样事上冒犯了你我真的很抱歉!.
I am truly sorry if I have offended you in any way.
Goodnight, Charles.
晚安,查理.
Goodnight, Leo.
晚安,Leo.
What the hell was that?
这是什么意思?
他认为他自己是从19世纪来的,查理.他认为自己是个公爵.
He thinks he's from the 19th century, Charlie. He thinks he's a duke.
I know.
我知道,
你不觉得很酷吗?不.
- Isn't that cool? - No.
Kate, he's in character. He is an actor.
Kate,他在演某个角色.他是个演员.
哦,是吗?演那一出戏?
Oh, really? For what show?
You know that just because someone doesn't have a paying gig...
你知道吗这是因为..有人没有付清公演的费用
...it doesn't mean they're not working on their craft.
这并不意味着平常就不能扮演自己的角色.
What's going on here?
这儿怎么了?
I think there's something wrong with his, uh...
我想是他那儿有什么东西不对了, 哇...
...thing.
-东西.
- Give me that telephone.  No.
把电话给我.不.
把它给我.不,我需要.....
- Give it to me. No, I need to...
What do you expect me to do? You took away my cell phone.
你想我会干吗?你把我的手机拿走了.
手机在医院里不允许使用.我必须要打个电话!
- They're not allowed on hospital property.  I have to make a phone call!
You're not going to make one now.
你现在不能打.
No, no, you don't understand. This is a very important phone call.
不,不.你不明白.这是一个很重要的电话.
I have to leave this hospital now. I can't be here anymore.
我现在就要离开医院.我再也不能在这儿呆了.
Besser先生我很烦老给你讲这些.
Mr. Besser, I am tired of telling you this.
You are not going nowhere until Dr. Feinstein signs your release!
你那儿都不能走直到Feinstein医生给你签了出院证明!
你是否了解过地球科学,Esther(名字),?
Did you ever take any earth science, Esther, hmm?
你看起来是个聪明女人.
You look like a smart woman.
Ever hear of the time-space continuum? Sounds important, doesn't it? Well, it is.
是否听说过时空联合体?听起来很重要,是不?哦,确实是.
You want to know something, Esther? It's broken! Okay?
还想知道些其他事吗,Esther?时空破了!明白吗?
And I'm the only guy who can fix it.
我是那个唯一可以修复的人.
So why don't you go down the hall there and get on your little telephone...
所以为什么你不下楼去拿起你的小电话
...and call Dr. Feinstein...
给Feinstein医生打个电话...
晚安Besser(斯图亚特)先生.你告诉他...
- Goodnight, Mr. Besser.  You tell him that...
You tell him that I...
告诉他我......
Point the toes, pull your shoulders back.
手指向脚趾,肩膀向回收.
作一个深呼吸现在向外呼气然后头朝后.
Take a deep breath in and then exhale into downward-facing dog.
Oh, be quiet! Be quiet... oh!
哦,安静!安静... 喔!
巴特,闭嘴!
Bart, shut up!
这个东西太危险了!这不过是个烤面包机!
- That thing is a damned hazard!  It's just a toaster!
Well, insertion of bread into that so-called toaster produces no toast at all...
就是把面包插进去所以叫烤面包机根本就烤不出面包来--
...merely warm bread! Inserting the bread twice produces charcoal.
只是把面包加热!把面包插入两次,烤出焦黄的面包.
这么清楚的说明如何正确烤出面包实际上需要插入一个和另外半个
So, clearly, to make proper toast it requires one and a half insertions...
看起来按说明书上说的用这个装置根本就不工作!
...which is something for which the apparatus doesn't begin to allow!
假如说这个电子设备的厂家在生产它之前他就应该先试用它.
One assumes that when the General of Electric built it he might have tried using it.
另外他应该为他的创造发明感到骄傲
One assumes the General might take pride in his creations...
...instead of just foisting them on an unsuspecting public.
而不是用它来糊弄大众.
You know something?
你知道吗?
没有人象你那样做
Nobody gives a rat's ass...
...that you have to push the toast down twice. You know why?
你应该把面包片插下去两次.知道为什么吗?
Because everybody pushes their toast down twice!
因为每个人都是把面包片插两次!
不是我来的那个地方那样.
Not where I come from.
哦.对了,你是来自于
Oh, because where you come from...
面包是烹饪研究的结果的那种地方.
...toast is the result of reflection and study.
是的,你在嘲笑我.
Yes, you mock me.
But perhaps one day, when you've awoken from a pleasant slumber...
但是,当有一天早晨从美梦中醒过来的时候
鼻子里闻到热乎乎的奶油蛋糕和上面涂着的柠檬香味的果酱还有新鲜的黄油的时候
...to the scent of a warm brioche smothered in marmalade and fresh creamery butter...
你就会知道什么才是真正的生活了这不是你需要做的什么事情只是一种享受.
...you'll understand that life is not solely comprised of tasks, but tastes.
Say that again.
再说一遍.
Pardon me?
什么意思?
-他们开始了吗?-是的.
- Did they start yet? - Yes.
Session list.
安排时刻表.
Leopold, Darci. Darci, Leopold.
Leopold,这是Darci.Darci,这是Leopold.
我想让他试一试.你可以在最后安排他试一试吗?
I'll like him to read. Can you tack him on at the end?
And, Leopold, go with Darci. She'll take you to the greenroom and explain everything.
Leopold,跟着Darci去.她会把你带到演员休息室给你解释一切的.
I need to work out. I need a place I can work out.
我要策划一下.我需要一个地方策划一下.
If I could get Mr. Duke? Is he ready? Where is he?
可以叫公爵先生过来了吗?他准备好了吗?他在那儿?
Oh, my God, look at this. Let's skip this one.
哦,天哪,看这些.这一点跳过不要.
Mr. Duke, right here on the floor.
公爵先生,就站在这儿.
-对不起,-这儿有个标记,就站这儿.就站在这个摄像线上.
Excuse me, that's your mark, right there. Just stand on that tape line.
Look, forget this guy. I can't waste any more time, J.J.
听着,忘了这些家伙.我再也不能浪费时间了, J.J.
We need to make a decision now.
我们现在需要作决定了.
All right, we've got plenty of good choices. Let's cut it off, Kate.
好的,我们现在有大量的选择了.kate,我们开始吧.
这是个错误, J.J.
That would be a mistake, J.J.
Kate,客户要求开始拍了.
Kate, the client wants to move on.
We should see this last guy. It'll... Two minutes!
我们该看看这最后一个家伙.要..两分钟!
我看他像个贵格会教徒.
I think he looks like the Quaker Oats guy.
行了Phil,这不管你的想法如何.主要是看客户的想法如何.
Well, Phil, it's really not about what you think. It's about what they think.
他们在这儿昏搞了一天了现在你看他们.
They've been in a coma all day and now look at them.
To them, this guy is a dream.
这个家伙对他们来讲是个梦想.
He's handsome, honest, courteous.
他很英俊,诚实,有礼貌.
Stands when you walk in a room. Brings you brioche in bed.
出镜你就会看到.他会让你带着奶油蛋卷上床去吃.
If you eat his margarine...
如果你吃他她推荐的人造黄油
...maybe your hips will shrink and he'll come to your door.
也许你会扭扭屁股然后再去排队购买.
I take it this is to be delivered in direct address as on Geronimo.
我就像是直接去上门送货那样?高呼勇敢.
- Geronimo?  He means Geraldo.
高呼勇敢?他的意思是像个英雄那样.
Exactly.
对.
好了, 大家都-- 请安静.开拍.
Okay, everyone... quiet please.  And action.
Start talking, bud.
讲话啊,伙计.
Fresh creamery butter.
新鲜的农场黄油.
Is there anything more comforting?
还有什么让你更感觉舒服的东西?
I say there is.
我告诉你还有.
And perhaps you'll agree when you sample fat-free Farmer's Bounty...
当你尝试了农场产品后
你一定会同意我的说法每咬一口都会感受到
...with the genuine essence of creamery butter in every bite.
With every mouthful of Farmer's Bounty you shall receive butter's...
真正的新鲜黄油.货真价实的,口感舒适的农场产品
...luxurious comfort in your mouth without adding to the luxury of your waistline.
你将放心,大胆的享受新鲜黄油而不但心增加你的腰围.
不错啊, Kate.你在那儿找到他的?
Not bad, Kate. Where'd you find him?
He lives in my building.
他住在我那幢楼.
Where do I sign? Right here, and here.
签在那儿?这儿,和这儿.
刚才干得太漂亮了,Kate.谢谢,J.J.
- That was spectacular, Kate. Thanks, J.J.
A lot to talk about tonight at dinner.
晚上晚餐的时候我们再谈.
- Nice work, Mr. Margarine. Thank you.
干得好,黄油先生.谢谢.
Outfit was a great idea. Nice.
这身服装真是个好主意.
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
- You seem pleased. Oh, you did so great in there!
你看起来很高兴.哦,你刚才在那儿干得太漂亮了!
Man!
伙计!
你将上国家电视台的广告时段了!
You are going to be on a national television spot!
I take it you're dining with that man tonight.
我猜你晚上要和那个男人去吃晚饭吧.
Huh? Oh, yeah, J.J. He's my boss.
什么?啊,是的, J.J.他是我的老板.
你需要一个陪伴.他的意图太明显了.
You require a chaperone. His intentions are obvious.
I'm alone with you. Do I need a chaperone?
我和你一起去.我需要一个陪伴吗?
We're not courting, Kate. If we were, as a man of honor...
我不是在向你献慇勤.如果是,作为一个男人
我会把我的想法通过书信的方式通知你.
...I would have informed you of my intentions in writing.
Good day.
你好.
Hey!
嗨!
Kate,我们为什么不坐这个.那些是给游客准备的.
- Kate, why don't we take one of these.  They're for tourists.
- Sorry, she doesn't seem interested.  Oh, hey, hello. Hello.
对不起,她对这个不感兴趣.哦,咳,喂,喂.
Hey! Hey!
咳!咳!
咳!咳,你.....
Hey! Hey, you...
Kate!
Hey, you asshole!
咳,你这个流氓!
I'm going to get you!
我要抓到你的!
Hey! Asshole!
咳!流氓!
Goddamn it.
该死.
把手伸给我.什么?
- Give me your hand.  What?
Your hand, woman!
你的手,女士!
你以为你在干什么?
What do you think you're doing?
我警告你,无赖!我在皇家军队学习过骑术
I warn you, scoundrel I was trained to ride at the King's Academy...
...and schooled in weaponry by the palace guard. You stand no chance.
在皇家护卫队学习过武器使用.你没有机会.
Where you run, I shall ride and when you stop, the steel of this strap will be lodged in your brain.
你跑到哪儿,我就骑到哪儿你只要一停下来,这根铁链子就会挂到你的脑袋上.
Your boyfriend's a very good rider.
你的男朋友是个好骑手.
是的.
Yeah.
这是真的吗?
Are you for real?
Pardon me?
什么?
Are you for real?
这是真的吗?
我想是的.
I believe so.
你是一个公爵.
You're a duke.
我出生在一个公爵家庭.
I was born a duke.
I've never felt like one.
我从来没有感觉自己像是个公爵.
待着别动,坐下.
Stay. Sit.
On your feet. Stay.
屁股坐下,待着.
Stay.
待着
好孩子.
Good boy.
I'm off to dinner. What are you two doing?
我要走了去吃晚餐.你们两个一会儿干吗?
I don't know. Maybe we'll watch the rest of the game or go out or something.
不知道.也许我们就在这儿看比赛或者出去逛逛.
哦,谢谢你.
Oh, thank you.
Kate, may I repeat my offer to serve as a chaperone?
Kate,我可以再说一次你是否需要一个陪伴吗?
No, thank you, Leopold.
不用,谢谢你,Leopold.
Charles, don't you find this inappropriate? As her brother, I would think...
查理,你不觉得这样不是太恰当吗?作为他的兄弟我想应该是..........
As her brother, I would think that my sister would invite me to an audition.
作为他的兄弟我想应该是...我姐姐应该要我去作为听众.
Could be just me, though. Seems kind, but...
而且只有是我.看起来像是,但是.....
-查理.
Charlie.
You're not exactly a margarine spokesperson.
你不是黄油发言人.
- I can't sell butter, Kate? I don't mean to be insulting...
我不能够卖黄油, Kate?我不是想对你无礼...
这就是无礼,我是个演员.你不信任我也可以做卖黄油的广告?
It's insulting. I'm an actor. You don't have faith in me to sell butter?
No. No. I'm sorry.
不,不.对不起.
I can do British, Kate. I'm an actor.
我能扮成英国人, Kate.我是个演员,
可以扮成任何人!你是个很棒,很棒的演员.
- I can be anybody!  You're a very, very good actor.
- I am a good actor.  You are.  Okay, fine.
-我是个好演员.-你是.好了,行了
all right. A Victorian dude who's never...
就这样.一个维多利亚的公爵从来没有
- ...seen a Mets game watching TV.  Okay.
看过电视里的比赛.好了.
Scene... I say, are those little people in that box of phosphorous?
场景(查理用英国口音模仿)我说就是这些小人在那个盒子里?
Crikey, I believe it is! This game's more beguiling than cricket!
哎呀,我真的相信!
(查理用英国口音的模仿)
Good golly, oh, Jesus! It looks like Mike Piazza just hit a game!
How about Canadian? Oh, right on. Right on, you like butter, huh? Yeah, what's that aboot?
加拿大口音如何?哦,行啊.行啊,你喜欢黄油,是吗?是啊,那个如何?
晚安.晚安.
- Good night. Good night.
...all those people up in that stadium. Know what they probably could go for? Some margarine!
...当所有的人走进运动场,知道他们是去干什么吗?一些黄油!
When your friend walked in in that outfit I was getting a little nervous for you there.
当你的朋友穿着那身制服走进来的时候我还真的有点为你担心.
"If you eat his margarine, maybe your hips will shrink." It's brilliant.
"如果你吃了这个黄油,也许你就会扭扭屁股."真是太精彩了.
你让Phil从他那难堪的境地中解脱出来.
You saved Phil from his own ambivalence.
我知道只有这种方法--靠我的直觉.
I knew it was the way to go... in my gut.
I'm counting on that gut.
我靠的就是你的这种直觉.
是否要给你们上点面包和一瓶35年的酒?
Can I get a bottle of your 95 Lynch-Bages and a bottle of Evian?
I'll tell you one thing... your friend is going to be bigger than Mr. Whipple.
我要告诉你你那个朋友将会比Whipple先生更伟大.
You're not sleeping with him, are you?
谢谢.你没有和他一起睡觉吧,是吗?
没有.
No.
Leo. Leo, come on. Come here.
Leo. Leo,过来,到这儿来.
怎么样,伙计?
How's it going, man?
See the girl with the long brown hair? That's Patrice.
看见那个长着棕色的长发女孩没有?那是Patrice(名字).
- She's lovely. She's mine.
她很可爱.她是我的.
恭喜你啊.
Congratulations.
Hey, everybody, this is Leo! Leo, this is everybody.
咳,兄弟们,这是Leo!Leo,这是我的朋友们.
- What's up? Dennis. Hello.
干吗呀?邓尼斯.
Shelby, Allison, Monica.
Shelby, Allison, Monica.(人名)
And this, this is the insatiable Patrice.
这个是不知足的Patrice.
- Hey, Charlie.. Hey. How do you do?
咳,查理.咳.你好?
- Patrice, let me assist you. Thanks.
Patrice,让我来帮你.谢谢.
You got it? I was going to get it.
你拿到了?
Let me get that for you.
我正准备去拿.我来帮你点.
给你.
There you go.
You look nice tonight. Very...
今晚你看起来真漂亮.非常...
像是个封面女郎.
Like a Judy Blume book.
这不错啊,我看了看这儿的水就像是护城河的水.
That's good, because I thought for a moment that body of water here was a moat.
No, that's a pond. The gardens are devastating.
不,是池塘的水.花园太漂亮了了.
They are. They're very, very beautiful. Ooh.
是的.它们真是太漂亮了.
你应该亲自过去看看.对,对.
- You'll have to come and see them firsthand. Right, right.
After the merger I'm going to be stuck over there, setting things up.
合并之后合并之后,我就会被安排在那边工作.
I'll be craving a little face time from my new top honcho in New York.
在纽约我的新老板手下工作我就更渴望有能和你见面的机会.
你在说什么?我是说你该来参观一下.
- What are you saying? I'm saying you should come visit.
- I'll fly you over for the weekend. Oh, yeah, I heard that.
或者我飞到你这儿来过周末.哦,是的,这个我听到了.
The other part... the part before that. The part about the top honcho.
另一部分--开始的那一部分.新老板前的那一部分.
I didn't understand that, that part.
我没有明白你讲的那一部分.
How about catching an opera Saturday? La Boheme's at the Met.
星期六有没有空去看一场歌剧?La Bohtes at the Met.(歌剧名)
Okay, so she comes back... the audience is about to leave...
然后,她走了回来--观众已经打算走了--
她重新回到台上并开始重新表演想感动观众用她那
...she comes back on stage and she starts squirting the audience with this turkey baster...
...filled with this pine mist.
充满了松脂油的喷雾器想弄出眼泪来.
And she's screaming "Un-sex me! Un-sex me!"
并且开始大叫"不要性骚扰,不要性骚扰!"
但是却一滴眼泪都没有.只是人的那种原始的激情.
But no tears. Just raw human passion.
- Isn't Willem Dafoe part of that group? Yeah, and he did this monologue about how...
是不是Willem Dafoe的那一段戏?是的,他发表了一通
...all the best things in life are hidden in people's basements.
人类最好的东西都藏于地下室中的论断.
像是卢浮宫.
Like the Louvre.
I'm sorry. You were saying, Charles?
对不起.刚才说的,查理?
就刚才..不,卢浮宫怎么样?
- Just... No, what about the Louvre?
告诉我们你刚才打算要讲的.
Tell us what you were going to say.
Well...
哦.
...only a fraction of the Louvre is on the walls. The rest is in the basement.
在卢浮宫只有一小部分东西是挂在墙上的.其余的都在地下室放着.
你曾经到过卢浮宫的地下室?啊,是的.
- You've been in the basement of the Louvre?  Oh, yes.
I was an art history major at Vassar.
我在Vassar学院主修的是艺术史.
And so, what's down there?
那,下面有些什么东西?
Well, that's where the real show begins. Unspoiled by dilettante.
实际上,下面才是些真东西.一些没有被业余爱好者损坏的东西.
DaVinci, Michelangelo, David, Chardin.
达芬奇,米开朗基诺，大卫,但丁.
"Allow me to assist you, Patrice. Oh, let me light that for you, Monica."
"让我来帮帮你,Patrice."我来帮你点烟Monica."这是干什么?"只是我朋友们的聚会.
"What, this? This is my family crest. Been in the family for..." Oh, in the basement?
"就是朋友聚会...哦,到了地下室?
"What do they have in the basement? Why, the works of da Vinci...
"地下室里有些什么?"为什么达芬奇
"米开朗基诺,但丁,大卫的作品
...Michelangelo, Chardin, David...
...all surrounded by great coral sponges to absorb the moisture."
都被一些巨大的海绵包围着以便吸收水气."
Just for the record, I was working it.
只是想重复你刚才的话,我正在努力.
I was in the zone and I would have gotten her number
我刚好讲到那个地方我想要她的电话号码
如果不是你把整个晚上变成卢浮宫的导游外.
if you hadn't turned the evening into a guided tour of the Louvre.
My apologies.
我向你道歉.
我就给你直说了吧.Patrice认为里你很可爱--也许是爽朗又可爱.
Let's get one thing straight. Patrice, she thought you were cute... probably gay and cute.
- And cute, Leo, that's the kiss of death.  Perhaps.
Leo,那可是死亡之吻.-也许.
-也许? 当然.我想这就是他的号码.
- Perhaps? Certainly.  I believe this is her number.
在我看来,Patrice对你的表现根本没有兴趣.这也难怪.
As I see it, Patrice has not an inkling of your affections. And it's no wonder.
You, Charles, are a merry-andrew.
你,查理,就像是个小丑.
- A what? Everything plays a farce to you.
一个什么?你就是在表演一出滑稽剧.
女人只对诚心实意作出反应.
Women respond to sincerity.
This requires pulling one's tongue from one's cheek.
这就要求不要乱嚼舌头,瞎表演.
No one wants to be romanced by a buffoon.
没人想和小丑罗曼蒂克.
现在,这个号码就可以打给她.好的.
- Now, that number rings her.  Yes.
- So ring her tomorrow. I can't. She gave the number to you.
-那就明天打给她吧.我不能.她把号码给的你.
她给我是因为我告诉她你的想法.
Only because I told her of your affections.
那,你给她说了什么?
Wha-What did you say?
Merely that you admired her but you were hesitant to make an overture...
不过说了你很喜欢她但是你对主动约会感到踌躇不安
...since you'll been told she was courting another.
知道某人告诉你有人向她求婚.
该死,真是太好了!
Shit. That's good!
- Wha-What did she say? She handed me the napkin.
那她说什么?她把写有号码的餐巾递给了我.
查理,现在太晚了.不,不.不.她还没有回家.
- Charles, it's quite late. No, no, no, she won't be home yet.
I get her machine, I leave a message ball's in her court.
她有留言机,我给她留个言
要想向她献慇勤.你得找个高兴的时候.要点就是:欲速则不达.
You're ladling calculation upon comedy. The point is, to keep the ball in your court.
你说得对,你说得对.
You're right. You're right.
好了.明天前什么都别做.
- Okay. Nothing need be done till tomorrow.
Tomorrow. Then I make my move.
明天，明天我就行动.
An overture, Charles. Make your intentions known.
主动出击,查理.向她表明你的意图.
想想如何让她高兴而不是让她烦恼.
Think of pleasing her, not vexing her.
No vexing.
不让她烦恼.
You're intoxicated. We should retire. I'm sure Kate will be home.
你已经陶醉了.我也该退休了.我想Kate应该回家了.
我看不一定.但现在快午夜了.
- I doubt it. But it's nearly midnight.
- You like her, don't you? Who?
你喜欢她，是吗?-谁?
-Kate.
Kate.
你就是!-噢，查理，别说了.
- You do! Oh, Charles, Charles.
You like my sister!
你喜欢我姐姐!
Well, you made your intentions known, right? Right?
好啊，你现在搞清楚自己的想法了,对吧?-对吧?
-你喝醉了.Leo,别...他们就在那儿附近.
- You've been drinking. Leo, Commune... right around the corner.
We could stop in, you could give me a couple of pointers...
我们可以去看看,你可以找个什么理由
然后在那儿坐下--随便说点什么.
...pull out a chair or two you could throw out a gesture here or there.
Yeah, see, it's one thing with Patrice. You don't give a shit.
对了，你看，这和我与Patrice是一回事.你一点也不够大胆.
就和刚才一样当你遇到一个你喜欢的女孩时?
It's a whole other ball of wax when it's a girl you like, huh?
Yeah, who's the merry-andrew now?
你现在变成小丑了?
你想让我的姐姐不高兴!
You want to vex my sister!
我不得不坦白的说我自己有点糊涂了.
I have to confess that I'm a little bit confused.
No. Thank you.
不，谢谢.
当你叫我今晚来吃饭的时候我的感觉是我们在这儿会讨论...
When you asked me to dinner tonight I was under the impression that we were here to discuss...
合并的事.是，对，是的.
- The merger. Yes. Right. Yes.
- And a possible promotion. Yes.
和晋升的可能性.是的.
是的,是那样.
Yes, that, too.
但是，现在晚餐快要结束了我们还没有讨论到
And, well, dinner is winding down and we haven't really discussed...
...anything even remotely relevant to what I thought we came here to...
任何切题的事情那些我来这儿以前想到的事情...
我简直没有想到会看到你这样的激动，Kate.你甚至还没有吻过我.
I don't believe I've ever seen you this flustered, Kate. You haven't even kissed me yet.
是.对.那是.....
Yeah. Right. Well...
I like you, J.J., I do. I like you quite a bit.
我喜欢你, J.J.,真的.我真的有点喜欢你.
但是事实上我想你会同意那是种工作.......
Um, as a matter of fact I think you would agree that a working...
一种成功的工作关系是一种在相互合作中产生的.....
...a successful working relationship requires a great deal of...
What exactly is our working relationship?
非常愉快的工作关系?
Hi, Kate!
嗨, Kate!
嗨,查理.
Hi, Charlie.
Well... what are you doing here?
你们怎么到这儿来了?
我们只是从这儿路过-顺便进来打个招呼.-J.J., 行吗?-行.
- We just thought we'll come by to say hi. J.J., right?  Right.
我可以和你讲句话吗?现在?
- Kate. Might I have a word with you? Now?
- In private. No! No.
-私下讲.不，不.
黄油先生.
Mr. Margarine.
请... 请和我们一起吧.
Please... please join us.
- And where did you say it is? In Sussex.
你刚才说那是在什么地方?-在苏克斯郡.
-靠近巴勒莫.-对.
- Near Ballmour. Yes.
-是18世纪建造的.早于18世纪.
- Built in the 18th century. Early 18th century.
Really? Are you quite sure?
是吗?你这么肯定?
- Yes. He's got pictures, Leopold.
是的.他有照片，Leopold.
Perhaps you were swindled, because I can assure you...
也许你在骗人,因为我可以象你保证
...as of the late 19th century there's nothing but farmland near Ballmour.
应该是在19世纪以后那时靠近巴勒莫那儿什么都没有只有农田.
-你搞错了.-那不可能.
- You're mistaken.  That's not possible.
是吗，确实是那样,Leopold,你搞错了.
Well, it's quite possible, Leopold, that you are mistaken.
不，我没有错.
No, it is not.
...那是那个郡唯一的一个庄园.我知道是因为我在那儿长大的.
...the only manor house in the county. I know because I grew up there.
Leopold, it wasn't...
Leopold,它是.....
- Leo, do you enjoy opera? I do. And do you?
Leo,喜欢歌剧吗?-喜欢，你喜欢吗?
-噢，喜欢.歌剧让我..感觉到生活.
Oh, yes. It keeps... keeps me alive.
你有什么喜爱的歌剧吗?Bohne. La Bohne.
- Do you have a favorite? Boheme. La Boheme.
I've seen it 12 times. That's... that's how I learned to speak French.
我看了12遍了.那个剧让我.. 让我开始学说法语.
你会讲法语?很流利.
- You speak French? Fluently.
What did he say?
他刚才说什么?
"How sweet your face looks gently encircled by the soft moonlight."
"你的脸在温柔的月光下看起来是多么的漂亮."
Oh, I like that.
噢，我喜欢.
From the opening scene of Boheme. A stunning duet.
这是Bohne那场剧的第一个场景.一个令人眩晕的二重唱.
- Andre sings it to Mimi. Andre...
Andre唱给Mimi的.Andre...
I invited Kate to the Met next week. She's never been.
我要请Kate下礼拜见面.她不会来.
Patrone is singing Andre, and she turned me down.
我向她示爱她却让我失望.
你可以解释这是为什么吗，Leopold?
Can you explain that, Leopold?
是这样..
Well...
La Boheme is one of man's great achievements and should not be missed.
歌剧中的男主角是个有抱负的男人确实不会让女士失望.
But perhaps Kate resists on moral grounds.
但是也许Kate拒绝是有她自己的道德基准.
为什么?
How so?
- Should we get the check? Well...
我们结帐了吧?
...some feel that to court a woman in one's employ...
有人觉得自己是上司就可以向蛇一样的去纠缠自己的下属
就一定能够得逞？.
...is nothing more than a serpentine effort to transform a lady to a whore.
J.J.
这个家伙很有魅力, Kate.
This guy's charming, Kate.
黄油公爵认为我是一条毒蛇.
The Duke of Margarine thinks me a serpent.
- No, he doesn't. No, not a serpent.
-不，他不是-不，不是条毒蛇.
That's too grand a word. Simply a braggart and a cad...
那样说太过火了.最多就是个自夸和粗俗的人而已
有谁会比我知道更多的法语.
...who knows less French than I, if that's possible.
顺便说一下在那出歌剧中没有Andre这个人.
And by the way there's no Andre in Boheme... it's Rudolfo.
And though it takes place in France it's rarely played in French...
尽管这事发生在法国但歌剧很少在法国上演,
...as it is written in Italian. Good night.
而且它是用意大利文写的.晚安.
Sorry.
对不起.
Kate, might I have a word?
Kate,可以给你讲句话吗?
- Morning. Hi.
-早晨好.-嗨.
- You want some coffee?  No, thanks.
-要不要点咖啡?-不,谢谢.
- You want to read... you want to read your paper?  No, thank you, Charlie.
你要不要读一下...读一下你的报纸再走?不了,谢谢,查理.
我要去上班了那吃点这个你洗干净了的水果.
I want to go to work and try and clean up this mess you made.
You sure you don't...
你肯定你不要..
Kate...噢, Kate!
Kate... Uh, Kate!
- What? - I-I just thought maybe you'll want a-a kiwi for-for-for the subway.
-什么?-我-我-只是想也许你想要个狝猴桃可以在地铁上吃.
- That's a papaya, Charlie. Oh. You're right. Okay.
那是蕃木瓜,查理.哦.你说得对,好吧.
But while using the product...
在我们使用这个产品的时候
80%的人发现这个产品太硬以至于不能...
...80% found the product too soft to be...
起到有效的作用.
...effective.
现在,这个给我们的市场研究人员推出了一个新的课题.
This, of course, presents a conundrum for us marketeers.
我们怎样能够在用保鲜膜存放东西的时候
How do we maintain a soft feel on the exterior of a plastic wrap or pack while retaining...
...the useful tensile strength in the sheets?
让外面感觉到是柔软的质地利用塑胶的扩展张力?
Now, I'm going to suggest to the Summer Soft people...
现在我建议将现有的产品在夏季
投放到欧美市场
...to scale back to a limited release of the product...
以便我们能够根据使用情况对这个产品继续开发
...in the mid-Atlantic states, where we can refine the product...
...on the basis of extensive...
根据使用情况再定...
亲爱的Katherine...(凯塞琳kate的全称)
Dearest Katherine...
I behaved as an imbecile last night...
我昨晚由于在晚会上喝了点酒表现出极度的愚蠢
...animated in part by drink...
在某种程度上讲是因为你的美丽
另反面也是因为我自己愚蠢的自得.
...in part by your beauty and in part by my own foolish pride.
And for that I am profoundly sorry.
对那些所作所为我深深的表示歉意.
Please accept as a gesture of apology...
请把这作为我的道歉吧
今晚8点在楼顶我为你准备的晚餐.
...a private dinner on the rooftop tonight at 8:00.
Okay, where are we on Farmer's Bounty?
好了,我们的农场产品怎样了?
Kate?
要不要拿出来给我们看看?
Care to share with us?
Farmer's Bounty?
农场产品?
讲到这个.
Where we are.
讲到这个非常好.
Where we are is good.
Um, as you know, we found our spokesperson.
嗯,就如你们知道的那样,我们找到了一个产品代言人.
The response room final showed a 96 in the top two boxes.
市场的反应率上升了96%.
His key female descriptors...
女性中对他的描述是...
英俊,罗曼蒂克
were "handsome", "romantic" with several write-ins of...
有人在调查表中写的是"真是个漂亮英俊的男人"
"What a hunk."
太好了.
Great.
J.J.?  J.J.?
J.J., hi.
J.J.,嗨.
Um, listen, I just want to apologize again
嗯,听着,我只是想再给你道个歉
for what happened last night. There was no need for things to get that way.
为昨天晚上发生的事情.不要再记着昨天那些事情了.
I appreciate that.
谢谢你.
那... 你没事吧?
So... everything's okay?
没事, Kate.
Yes, Kate.
I didn't jump; I fell.
我没有跳,我只是感觉.
There's a difference... a subtle difference, but nonetheless a difference.
有点不一样--很微妙的感觉,但反正不一样.
- So, why did you fall down there? Because there was no elevator.
那么你是如何掉下去的呢?因为电梯没有在那儿.
And you feel that was your fault?
你觉得那是你自己的错误?
你看...
Look...
You know what, I'm sorry.
你知道吗,我很抱歉.
I got to concede that you are a very busy man...
我不得不承认你是个非常忙的人
...and I'm sure there are plenty of people clamoring for your particular brand of attention.
而且外面还有很多的病人在等着你需要你特别的治疗.(马丁医生,精神病学家)
Unfortunately, I am not one of them.
不幸的,我不是他们其中之一.
So if you don't mind, would you please unlock this door?
如果你不介意,麻烦你打开这扇们?
我只是担心你会伤害你自己.
I'm concerned you might be a danger to yourself.
And in such cases...
你这种病例
- Will someone please open... Aah! Aah! ...state law requires that I keep you under...
-喂?!-本州的法律要求置留你在...有人可以帮我打开... 啊!啊!
靠！
Fuck!
Everything all right, Dr. Geisler?
没事吧,Geisler医生?
Yes, Gretchen. Everything's fine.
没事Gretchen.很好,没事.
斯图亚特,我要给你用一种叫做普洛宁锌的药.
Stuart, I'm going to prescribe something called Prolixin.
It's a mild antipsychotic. Nothing too strong.
一种温和的精神病类药.药效不会太厉害.
"I was wondering... I was wondering if you would like to accompany me..."
"我只是在想..."我只是在想你是否愿意和我一起....
"如果你事先已经有安排..我明白.
"If you've already been previously engaged I understand."
Tonight at 7:00, 7:30. Please don't be late.
今晚7点半.请不要迟到了.
我有话要给你讲,行吗?因为你写的那些东西中有一些我讲不出来.
你给Patrice买了一束花没有?
Did you assemble a bouquet for Patrice?
听着,你不能这样说一位女士..."雅致,文静."
Look, you just can't tell a woman she's... "gracefully serene".
No, no, this will not do.
不,不,这个不行.
Wha... Why? What is wrong with this one?
为什么?这个为什么不行?
The orange lily implies extreme hatred.
橙色的百合花暗示着极端的憎恨.
The begonia and lavender danger and suspicion, respectively.
秋海棠和熏衣草分别代表危险和疑心.
每样花都有自己的意义,查理.
Every flower has a meaning, Charles.
Might I suggest the amaryllis...
我建议用桂顶红,
...which declares the recipient a most splendid beauty.
它代表宽容与接受它总是光彩照人.
或者用蔷薇花.
Or the cabbage rose.
Darci! Darci!
- What is this? It's a reply to Leopold's invitation.
-这是什么?-这是个答复-给Leopold的邀请函的答复
你要去,对吧?
You're going, right?
I haven't decided yet.
我还没有确定.
Oh, you haven't decided if you want to have dinner on your rooftop with a duke?
哦,你还没有确定是否要..到楼顶上去和公爵吃饭?
Who thinks he's from 1876! No!
谁会认为他是来自于1876年!不!
不过我还是要感谢...Kate,行了,好吧?
- And I would appreciate it if...  Kate, come on, okay?
我不知道到底他为什么让你觉得讨厌
I don't know what this guy did to piss you off...
...but that is the best apology letter in the history of mankind.
但是我知道那封道歉信是人类历史上最完美的一封.
-签了吧, Kate.现在才4点半,我给他传真过去.
Just sign it, Kate. It's 4:30. We'll fax it.
Kate McKay's office.
Kate McKay办公室.
They hung up.
他们挂了.
Hi. Is Patrice there?
嗨,是Patrice吗?
嗨, Patrice?
Hey, Patrice?
Hi. It's me, Charlie.
嗨.是我,查理.
- Hey, Charlie. I was just calling to find out...
嗨,查理.
...if you got my flowers... your flowers.
我打电话给你只是想知道你是否收到我的花-你的花.
I was calling to see if you got the flowers I sent you.
我打电话给你看你是否收到我送给你的花.
Yeah, I did.
对,是我送的.
同时我想问你是否愿意今晚出去和我看一场电影
And I was just wondering if you would like to go to a movie tonight...
...and maybe afterwards perhaps accompany me to dinner?
然后看完电影后再和我一起去吃晚饭?
I mean, I... I understand completely if you're otherwise engaged.
我是说...我非常清楚有人在追求你.
But, uh, you know, I just wanted to say that, um...
但是,你知道,我只是想给你说...
Yeah?
啥？
I wanted to say that you've, uh...
我是想说...你.....
...you've made an impression on me.
你给我留下了很深的印象.
And-and it-it's not just the way you look...
我..我是说你看起来--
I mean, which are great. Your looks are, you know, top-top shelf. But, uh...
我是说你很漂亮.你看起来是最完美的.但是...哦...
I don't know, it's, um...
我不知道该说什么,你是...
什么?
What?
你很优雅.
You're graceful.
You know, the way you move and speak.
知道吗,你走路,你说话的样子.
我的意思是,其他人也许会有更好的语言来描述
I mean, some people have a way with words and, you know, you...
知道吗,就是这样.
...you do.
最后我要说的是,我喜欢你!.
The bottom line is, I like you.
Patrice? Patrice?
What about 7:00?
7点如何?
7点?
7:00?
7:00 would be heaven. Okay.
7点简直太好了.
See you then.
到时候见.
真的有用!
It worked! It worked cool!
真是有用,太酷了!谁会和Patrice外出约会?查理会和Patrice去约会!查理会去.
Who's going out with Patrice? Charlie's going out with Patrice! Charlie's going over there.
Oh, better go get ready. Better go get changed.
哦,最好赶紧去准备.赶紧去换身衣服.
不要搞得太复杂因为她是喜欢我这个人.
查理,你看起来太棒了.
- Hey. Charlie, you look fantastic.
- Yeah?  Yeah.
-是吗-是的.
I got a date. I got to go.
我要去约会.我要走了,
再见.再见.
- Bye.  Bye.
- Kate?   Yeah?
Kate?什么?
嗯,今晚过一个愉快的晚上.
Um, have a good time tonight.
Bye.
再见.
My God.
我的天.
真是太美了.
This is beautiful.
真是不知道如何用语言来描述.
The very word for which I was searching.
May I?
可以吗?
我的妈妈非常的罗曼蒂克.
She was a real romantic, my mom.
When Prince Charles and Lady Di got married, she had a party.
当查理斯王子和戴安娜公主结婚的时候她办了个晚会.
她做了些煎饼和果酱.
She made crumpets and jam.
就像是美国超级橄榄球赛时那样的晚会.
It was like a Super Bowl party, but for moms.
She cried for a week.
她还为此苦了一个星期.
I don't know the story of Prince Charles and Lady Di.
我不知道这个故事查理斯和戴安娜女士的故事.
哦,你不会想知道的.这是一个有寓意的故事.证明...
Oh, you don't want to. It's a cautionary tale. Further proof.
- Of what?  You can't live a fairy tale.
证明什么?你不能生活在童话中.
I'm not very good with men.
我和男士不一定能相处很好.
Perhaps you haven't found the right one.
也许你还没有找到一个合适的罢了.
Maybe.
也许.
Or, uh, maybe the whole love thing is just a grown-up version of Santa Claus...
或者所有的爱情故事都是圣诞老人的翻版
都是我们从小受到的童话感染的结果
just a myth we've been fed since childhood...
...so we keep buying magazines and joining clubs...
所以我们不停的买杂志参加各种俱乐部
...and doing therapy and watching movies with hit pop songs...
接受各种治疗还有看电影,唱摇滚
把自己置身于爱情的蒙太奇中
...played over love montages...
...all in this pathetic attempt...
所有的这种努力都是想从圣诞老人的烟囱中
...to explain why our love Santa keeps getting caught in the chimney..
找回童年时的那种梦想.
Otis总是给我说爱情是一种飞跃.
Otis always told me love is a leap.
Lamentably, I was never inspired to jump.
令人惋惜的是我还从来没有这样的灵感.
By my 30th birthday, I had, according to my uncle, become a blemish on the family name.
在我30岁的时候,按照我叔叔的说法我成了我家族的败类.
So he brought me to this country with the proviso I marry an American.
于是他把我带到了这个国家附带条件是我必须在这儿.
A girl with a good deal of, um...
和一个有很多(钱)的美国姑娘结婚...
Charm?
迷人的?
Money.
钱.
Since my parents died our family fortune had become, shall we say, depleted.
自打我父母死了以后我们家的财产逐渐耗尽了.
I would be married now if I hadn't followed Stuart. I was to announce a bride that night.
如果不是跟着斯图亚特来这儿我应该已经结婚了.那天晚上我要宣布谁是我的新娘.
谁?
Who?
I don't know.
我不知道.
Someone. One of them.
某人.她们其中之一.
你干吗?
What are you doing?
我把它倒掉.
I'm just cleaning up.
Would you do me the honor of a dance?
愿意和我跳个舞吗?
请?
Please?
我不太擅长跳舞.
I am not much of a dancer.
You're doing famously, then.
你马上就会跳得很好的.
Leopold, NLeopold...
这真是太可爱了.
...this was lovely.
But I don't know if I can leap even if I am inspired.
但是我不知道我是否能有一个飞跃即使是我有这样的灵感.
People might think I'm brave, but I'm not.
也许人们认为我很勇敢,但其实我不是.
The brave are simply those with the clearest vision...
勇敢有一个更简单的解释
尽管喜悦和危险同在.
...of what is before them.
Glory and danger alike and notwithstanding, go out to meet it.
直接勇敢的面对就行了.
嗨.
Hey.
Morning, Charles.
早晨好,查理.
昨天傍晚和Patrice过得怎样?
How was your evening with Patrice?
很好,
Good.
不错.
Nice.
你过得怎样?
How was yours?
Good.
很好,
Nice.
不错.
好了,Leo,你不觉得现在该告诉我你到底是谁了吗?
So, Leo, don't you think it's time you tell me who you are?
你什么意思?我是说...
- What do you mean? I mean...
...it's a blast doing the duke thing with you 24/7, but...
你那个公爵的故事确实是让人难以接受
...I don't want to see Kate go through Stuart: The Sequel.
我真不想看到kate又出现和斯图亚特分手事再现.
I know she seems pretty tough but she hasn't had it that easy.
我知道她看起来相当的坚强但是她能挺过来也不容易.
She's always getting stuck with people who don't hold up their end.
她是那种经常无法摆脱自己过去的人.
Like me.
就像我,
- I just don't... I understand, Charles.
我经常...我明白,查理.
- You do?  Yes.
你明白?是的.
那...
So...
...who are you?
你到底是谁?
I am the man who loves your sister.
我是一个男人,一个爱你姐姐的男人.
好了,门打开.
Okay, door's open.
Shut the lid.
盖上盖子.
Push the drawers in.
把衣服放进去.
关上门,然后
Close the door, and...
...you push this button.
你按这个按钮.
A word to the wise: Don't press that till she wakes up.
给你出个点子在她醒来之前不要按.
这样她就可以看见你在洗衣了.
So she sees you doing it.
Oh, clever. The proverbial tree in the woods.
哦,聪明.谚语这样说的:一个男人洗碟子,
If a man washes a dish and no one sees it...
就好比树在森林里那是没人能够看见的...
有用吗?有用.
- Did it happen? Right.
- A cup of coffee, my dear. Thank you.
来杯咖啡,亲爱的.谢谢.
Breakfast?
早餐?
Nine-grain toast with strawberries and mascarpone, madame.
一片涂着草莓酱和义大利乳酪的面包,女士.
It's...
那是...
...apparently low...
很显然没有
...in polyunsaturates.
一点脂肪.
It's really good.
真是太好了.
It's good.
太好了
今天我们干什么?
What should we do today?
Oh no, no, no, no, no, no.
哦,别,别.....
谢谢,别.
Thank you. No.
You know what makes me happy? You don't look good in those.
你知道为什么让我笑吗?
They're so completely inappropriate for you.
你带上那个不好看.那个眼镜一点也不适合你.
Kate. Kate.
Kate, Kate,过来.
Kate, Kate, come.
Leopold? Leopold?
嗨,你要干什么?真没想到它还立在那儿.
- Hey, what are you doing?  It boggles the mind that it is still here.
This is my uncle's home. Well, was. This is where I lived.
这是我叔叔的家.曾经是.这是我住过的地方.
Good Lord.
天哪.
我父母的肖像画...还有我.
A portrait of my parents... and me.
Uh... uh, Leopold?
哦... 哦, Leopold?
Look, I just don't think that we should just be barging around here like that.
听着, 我只是觉得我们不应该就这样鲁莽的闯进来.
Leopold? Leopold?
My old quarters.
我的卧室.
What are you doing?
你干吗?
The place where I put everything I most cared for.
我放我最秘密的东西的地方.
Things I didn't want my uncle to touch.
那些我不想要我叔叔看到的东西.
My mother's ring.
母亲的戒指.
哦,真漂亮.
Oh, it's beautiful.
You know, I live on an island...
知道吗,我住在一个岛上
...connected to everything by bridges...
所有的东西都通过大桥与外界连接
我却从来没有走过那大桥.
...and I never cross them.
I've lived here for ten years, and I've...
我在这儿住了十年
...never been to the other side of anything.
我却从来没有到过桥的那一边去看看.
你从来没有旅行过?
You've never traveled?
没有.
No.
Do you...
你想......
什么?
What?
Do you miss where you're from?
你思念你来的那个地方吗?
In a way, I...
某种程度上来讲,我........
我想,..
I miss...
I miss its rhythm.
我想念那种节奏.
It was slower?
很慢吗?
Quite a bit slower.
非常慢.
- Like today? Yes.
就像今天?对.
- Do you hear that, Leopold? Do you hear that music?  Yes.
无论你到那儿,我将跟随着你(歌词)..听到了吗, Leopold?-听到那音乐了吗?-是.
看过那部电影吗-《帝凡尼的早餐》?
Have you ever seen the movie Breakfast a Tiffany's?
- Uh, no.  "No."
哦,没有."没有."
Not yet.
还没有.
你看见下面亮灯那儿那个家伙吗?嗯.
- You see that guy down there with the light on? - Mm-hmm.
He listens to the soundtrack...
他每天晚上都听
...of Breakfast at Tiffany's every night until exactly midnight.
"在帝凡尼的早餐"中的那首曲子
直到午夜.然后他关掉灯睡觉.
And then he turns his light off... goes to sleep.
Oh, that means it's Sunday. Oh, I don't want it to be Sunday.
哦,现在是星期天了.我不想是星期天.
我想更多的这样的日子.更多的1876年.
I want more of this. More 1876.
但是,kate,星期天不是不上班吗.我们还可以有更多.
But, Kate, you don't work on Sundays. We can have more.
不,不.因为星期天是....我又要工作的前一天...
...it gets poisoned.
我已经中了毒了.
I see.
我明白.
Besides, tomorrow is the day we shoot your commercial.
另外,明天我们还要拍你那条商业广告.
Kate.
Kate.嗯?
你是否愿意...?
Would you...?
Might you ever...
你是否.....
...consider...?
...考虑...?嗯?
It's time for bed.
该上床睡觉了.
- I'm so relaxed.  That's all right.
我太放松了.没事.
- You're tucking me in.  Yes.
你把我抱进来的.是的.
哈,你是我的Otis(仆人的名字).
Huh, you're my Otis.
Yes, Your Grace.
是,大人.
哦,等等.
Oh, wait.
Hey, hey, don't... don't go upstairs. Stay.
嗨,嗨,别......别上楼去.待在这儿
I love you, Kate McKay.
我爱你, Kate McKay.
烤饼,大人?
Scone, Your Grace?
Ah, thank you, Millard.
哦,谢谢, Millard.
- And you brought the Farmer's Bounty?  But of course.
你给我拿来的是"农场产品"?当然.
啊!新鲜的黄油.
Ah! Fresh creamery butter.
Is there anything more comforting?
还有什么让人更舒服的东西?
I say there is...
我告诉你,有!
也许你会赞同我的说法每咬一口都会感受到
...and perhaps you'll agree when you sample fat-free Farmer's Bounty...
...with the genuine essence of creamery butter in every bite.
真正的新鲜黄油
With every mouthful of Farmer's Bounty...
货真价实的,口感舒适的农场产品.
你将放心,大胆的享受新鲜黄油
...you shall receive butter's luxurious comfort in your mouth...
...without adding to the luxury of your waistline.
满足你的饕餮快感而不担心增加你的腰围.
- Farmer's Bounty.  Now, on this one
-农场产品.现在,就这样
咬一口,再微笑.
...take a bite and smile.
And... cut! All right, check gate.
现在.. 停!好了,检查胶片.
Good enough for me. Can we get a Dedo up here and something...
-够好了.
哦,对不起.对不起.
Oh, excuse me. Excuse me.
Is this an actual sample of Farmer's Bounty?
这就是农场产品拿来的样品吗?
是啊,怎么了?
Yeah. Why?
这个尝起来就像是洗马鞍的肥皂.那个不是你现在操心的问题,对吧?
- This tastes like saddle soap. Well, that's not really your concern, now, is it?
Not my concern? This product tastes like raw suet.
不是我操心的?这个产品尝起来就像是生的羊板油.
- How is that not my concern? Hey, pal, it's a paycheck!
为什么不是该我关心的?嗨,伙计,这只是拿钱办事!
-等一下.-拿钱办事?
- Wait a minute. Paycheck?
A... This is an outrage! Don't worry about the taste. Come back.
这... 这是一种欺骗!不要操心口感问题.回来.
- We need another shot.  Something that brings the light up on this...
我们还要拍另外一个镜头.
Leopold.
Leopold!
嗨! Leopold,到底怎么了?你干什么啊?他们需要你回到摄影棚去.
Leopold, what's going on? What are you doing? They-they need you back in there.
Do they?
他们需要?
Yeah. They have to shoot the rest of the spot. They're not finished yet.
对,他们还要拍其他的镜头.他们还没有拍完.
Well, I want no part of it.
哦,我不想再拍了.
- Why? Have you tasted it?
为什么?你尝过吗?
- Farmer's Bounty? Yes, Farmer's Bounty.
农场产品?对,农场产品.
是啊,我尝过了.这让人恶心.
- Yeah, I've tasted it. It's revolting.
I know.
我知道.
You know it's revolting yet you have no qualms enlisting me to endorse it?
你知道这很恶心你还仍然要我来干这个事情?
It's diet...
这是食品
...it's supposed to be awful. I mean, what is the problem?
即使是它有点难吃我是说到底是什么问题?
The problem is that for no reason beyond my affection for you...
问题就是....我受你的影响
我发现我自己在愚弄大众.
...I find myself peddling pond scum to an unsuspecting public.
嗨,听着,你知道吗我把我的事业全押在这上面了.
Hey, listen, you know the stakes are very high for me here.
- You can't just quit because...  Yes, I can. And so can you.
你不能就这样不干了，因为...是，我能，你也能.
当一个人发现自己干的事情是不值得干的时候他可以...
When one finds oneself participating in an endeavor entirely without merit...
撤退不干.不，不，
- ...one withdraws. No. No.
Because sometimes you have to do things that you don't like.
因为有的时候你不得不干一些你自己不愿意干的事情.
有些时候你不得不忍着点干完你已经开始干的事情.这是生活的一部分.
Sometimes you have to suck it up and finish what you started. It's part of life.
你说的话就像是我叔父说的.
You sound like my uncle.
Look, Leopold...
听着,Leopold
森食品公司是我们公司的一个重要客户.
...Jansen Foods is a very important account for my company.
If you don't go back in there then I get into a lot of trouble.
如果你不回去继续拍我会惹上很大的麻烦.
这个就是你在做的工作, Kate?
Is this what you do at work, Kate?
市场研究，蒙骗大众?
Research methods to deceive people?
Refine lies until they resemble truth?
装饰谎言掩盖真实?
It's no wonder you dread your work week.
这让我明白了你为什么你害怕你每周的工作.
- Oh! Man, I don't have time for this.  What has happened to the world?
噢，算了。我没有时间给你说这些.这个世界到底发生了什么变化?
You have every convenience, every comfort yet no time for integrity.
现在有这么多的方便的舒适的东西享受但却没有时间表现诚实.
No. What I don't have time for are pious speeches..
不，我现在没有时间在一个不会整天工作的
200岁的人面前说这些大话.
...by 200-year-old men who've never had to work a day in their life.
You have no idea what I've done with my life.
你不会知道我的生活会是怎么样的.
And you-you have no idea what I've done with mine!
那你，你也不会知道我的生活是怎么样的!
我能够有这样方便舒适的生活Leopold,
I haven't had all that many comforts and conveniences, Leopold...
...because I've been paying dues all of my life...
是因为我整天忙碌的工作
...and I'm tired, and I need a rest...
我现在累了，很想休息
但是如果我必须为生活去沿街叫卖的话我还是得去.
...and if I have to peddle a little pond scum to get one then so be it.
Very well.
那好吧.
We're kidding ourselves, Leopold.
我们在骗自己Leopold.
In point of fact I don't even really know who you are.
事实上我甚至还不知道你是谁.
You still don't believe I'm the man I say I am?
你还是不相信我就是我告诉你的那样?
We had a great weekend; that's that.
我们过了一个愉快的周末就那样.
现在是星期天了.都结束了.
And now it's Sunday. It's over.
There's such a lot of world...
有这样一个世界需要
去了解（歌词）...
...to see...
I know.
我知道.
I know, I know, it sounds crazy...
我知道，我知道,这听起来有点疯狂--
...talking about...
我说的在...
在东河上发现了时间的裂缝.
...finding a crack in time under the East River.
但是重点是，事实上是, Gretchen（人名）你知道吗...
But in, in point, in point fact, Gretchen you know...
...it is no more crazy than, uh...
这不比一只狗
发现了彩虹更疯狂.
a dog finding a rainbow.
Dogs are color-blind, Gretchen.
狗是色盲,Gretchen.
它们看不见颜色.
They don't see color.
是吗?就像我们看不见时间一样.
- Really? Just like we can't see time.
We can feel it.
我们可以感觉时间.
Oh... we can feel it passing...
噢... 我们可以感觉时间的流逝
但是我们不能看见，这是模糊的.
...but, uh, we can't see it; it's just a blur.
It's like, uh...
这就像是, 嗯...
...it's like we're riding in a, in a supersonic train...
就像是我们坐在超音速的列车上
整个世界在我们旁边晃过.
...and the world is just blowing by.
But imagine if we could stop that train, Gretchen. Hmm?
但是如果想像我们可以让列车停下,Gretchen.如何?
Imagine if we could stop that train...
想像我们可以停下列车
下车去，
...get out...
...look around and see time for what it really is.
到处看看，看看时间到底是什么样子.
A universe...
是宇宙，
世界这就象
...a world a thing as unimaginable as...
...color to a dog.
颜色对一只狗来讲
And as real...
是不可想像的事情.
时间就会是可触摸的东西，就像是你现在坐着的椅子.
...and tangible as that chair you're sitting in.
Now, if we could see it like that...
现在，如果你能够看到
...I mean, really look at it...
我是说真正的看到时间
那，
...then...
...maybe we could see the flaws as well as the form.
你就可以看到时间的裂缝是怎样生成的.
And that's it.
就是那样了.
It's that simple.
就这么简单.
That's all I discovered. I'm just a...
那就是我所发现的.我只是...
...just a guy who saw a crack in a chair...
我只是那个可以看到裂缝的人
而其他的人看不到.
...that no one else could see.
I'm that dog who saw a rainbow.
我就是那只可以看到彩虹的狗.
Only, uh...
只是...
...none of the other dogs believe me.
只是其他的狗不相信我.
I believe you.
我相信你.
I can see that some...
我看到
发生了一些事情.
things have...
...happened since I went away.
..从我走了以后
But...
但...
你必须回去.
...you have to go back.
You understand you'll be going back to the same day you left...
你明白你必须回去回到你离开的那一天
- ...April 28. Yes.
4月28日.是的.
那你知道你也许会重复一些事情.
So you understand you might be repeating a few things.
You might even see me.
你还会看到我.
Just don't follow me this time.
只是这次不要跟着我了.
Can I go in?
可以进来吗?
- J.J., you asked to see me?  Come on in.
J.J., 你想要见我?进来.
I understand you, uh, put out a fire at the shoot yesterday.
我知道你昨天..在拍片的时候救了场.
我猜估计是公爵先生的自我意识作怪?
Guess Mr. Duke's got a bit of an ego on him, huh?
Yeah.
是的.
I'm going to England this week...
我这周到英国去
...and I made a decision.
我已经决定了.
你将当纽约分公司的头儿.
You're going to be the top New York honcho.
那。这就是你的办公室了.
So, this is going to be your office.
我今晚将正式公布这事.
I'll be making it official tonight.
Thank you, J.J. Thank you.
谢谢你, J.J.谢谢.
You earned it.
你应得的.
我把全盘买下NFTC东西的合同
I'm heading over to Jansen to sign...
the buy-out papers, FTC stuff. So...
交给Jeshen去签字了.好了
那我们晚点见.
...I'll see you later at the thing.
-他说什么?-我得到了.
- What did he say? I got it.
- Oh, my God, that's wonderful! Just give me one second, I'm sorry, Darci. One second.
哦，天哪,太好了!等一下,对不起，Darci.等一下.
嗨，你接通了斯图亚特的电话.请留下消息.
Hi. You've reached Stuart. Please leave a message.
喂?
Hello?
Leopold,我不知道你在什么地方但是如果你在那儿,请把电话拿起来.
Leopold, I-I don't know where you are but if you're there, please pick up.
I got it.
我得到了.
我得到那个工作了.
I got the job.
I'm the new senior vice president at CRG.
我是新的付总裁了是CRG的副总裁.
哦，请给我回电话.
Uh, please call me. I, um...
I'm sorry about the way things came down yesterday.
我，我很抱歉昨天发生的那些事情.
I apologize. I, uh...
我道歉.
I just really need to see you. I'll love to see you tonight...
我..我真的想见到你.我希望晚上见到你
我现在还有一些关于农场产品的事情.我想晚点见你.
...but I have this thing at Farmer's Bounty. But I'll love to see you later.
I miss you.
我想你.
嗨，斯图亚特.
Hey, Stuart.
感觉如何?
How you feeling?
Where's Leo?
Leo到那儿去了?
他回家了.
He went home.
He was for real.
他是真的.
Holy shit!
天哪，该死!
快看这个!
Look at this!
Oh, my God.
哦，我的天.
冷冻，明白吗?冷冻.
Chilled, do you understand? Chilled.
And be sure to leave another case of the Chateau Marid.
必定要离开另外一个城堡.
是的，先生.
Yes, sir.
Leopold!
Leopold! Where have you been?
Leopold!你到那儿去了？!
Otis, I demand explication! It's half past 5:00! He's not even dressed!
Otis,我需要一个解释!现在已经5点半了!他还没有打扮好!
He'll be ready, my lord, I assure you.
他马上就好。我的主人,我保证.
我不是要马上就好.我是要他光彩照人!
I don't want him ready. I want him resplendent!
Here's the invitation. You've got your table number, your car number...
这个是邀请函.你的桌号，汽车牌号
我已经通知了那个家伙.他在麦迪森大楼.还有，你的来电的清单.
...and I've got Morty down there the guy you like. He's on the Madison side. Also, your phone sheet is in here.
And Stuart called you a couple times. So...
斯图亚特打了好几次电话给你.
have a great time tonight. You look beautiful.
祝你过一个愉快的晚上.你看上去漂亮极了.
我觉得我们没有走对地方.我想我们是要到麦迪森2640号.
I don't think this is right. I'm supposed to be going to 2640 Madison.
That's where we are, Miss McKay.
就是这儿了,McKay小姐.
Have a nice evening.
晚上好.
嗨.
Hello.
Hello. Invitation, please.
你好.请出示邀请函,
They're still plugs. They're just randomly seeded with Minoxidil.
好的.
对不起.
- No cornrows. Excuse me.
Hey, Kate. Congratulations.
嗨，Kate.恭喜你.
Thank you.
谢谢.
The hell with facelifts.
I'm into mini-lifts now. Just a tiny little bit each year.
I hear they're bringing back the 840 next year. So I'm just running out the lease.
-Kate,恭喜你.-谢谢你，Bob.
- Kate, congratulations.  Thanks, Bob.
- Hey, Kate. J.J. Hi, Barry.
嗨, Kate.-恭喜-J.J.嗨, Barry.
谢谢，非常感谢.
- Congratulations. Thank you. Thank you very much.
Anyway, I'm just glad they've got them fixed.
不管怎样，他们终于把它修好了.
要不我都准备把办公室搬到过道去了.
I was going to move my office down to the lobby.
对不起.
Excuse me.
Kate,不要走得太远了.我马上就要做个发言再过几分钟.
Kate, don't powder your nose for too long. I'm going to give this speech in a couple minutes.
Okay.
好的.
All this time I thought that I had pretzled fate...
我原来考虑的所有事情都是一个谜团
现在都解开了.但是为什么我从来没有想到过
...and it had to be untwisted. But what I never considered...
本来这个事情就是一个谜团.
...is that the whole thing is a pretzel.
A beautiful 4D pretzel of kismetic inevitability.
一个漂亮的4D的谜团，一个不可逃避的命运.
好了，你知道吗,在公园停车尽快赶到麦迪森楼去.
Okay, you know what, get off Park as soon as you can, and then go up Madison.
I was supposed to go back.
我应该马上赶回去.
He was supposed to come forward then he was supposed to go back again and...
他却要到未来来，然后他应该马上又回去...
...so was she.
她也是.
Now it is my pleasure and honor...
...to take priests to the bell tower.
...把神甫带到钟楼上.
你在谈进步与发明.
You speak of progress and invention.
But what I offer you down the stairs is reality.
但是我叫你下楼，这才是现实.
Take a wife. Marry.
找个妻子.结婚.
Let us not bother with this banter, Uncle.
我们不要再开玩笑了,叔父.
告诉我你想让谁与我结婚.那一个钱最多.
Tell me whom you want me to marry. Well, who has the most money.
Well...
...that would be Miss Tree of the Trees of Schenectady.
那应该是tree小姐，Schenectady家族的tree小姐.
好的.
Good.
Consider it done.
决定好了.
Otis,去把戒指拿来.我会在午夜宣布我的决定.
Otis, fetch the ring. I will announce at midnight.
- Invitation, please. Uh, hello. My name is Stuart Besser.
请出示请柬.噢，你好.我叫斯图亚特.贝塞耳.
I'm sorry, I know we're not on your list but his sister is Kate McKay;
对不起，我知道我们没有在名单上但是他的姐姐是Kate McKay;
她在这儿工作.对不起，我不能让你们进去.
- ...she works here. I'm sorry, sir, I can't just let you in.
...and I learned that there was one thing that I could do...
...我知道了我能够做一件事情...
...and it didn't require money and it didn't require a fancy school.
这不需要金钱这也不需要更多的训练.
I learned that I could please people.
我知道了我可以让人们高兴.
And there is nothing wrong with that!
这一点没错!
I am a people pleaser, people!
我是个开心大众的人, 大众!
非常感谢.我很...
Thank you so much. I am so...
Kate!
Stuart! Charlie! What are you doing?
斯图亚特!查理！你们来干什么?
看一下这些照片，Kate.
Take a look at these pictures, Kate.
- No! No-no-no-no! Now it's time to introduce the woman...
不! 不－不－不!现在，我要给你们介绍以为女士
...who's going to be holding down the fort in our New York offices...
她将负责我们在纽约的公司
我们刚刚升起的一颗新星,Kate McKay小姐!
...our own little rising star, Miss Kate McKay!
- They're introducing me downstairs right now!  Just listen to me for a second, okay, please?
你们听我说好吧?他们在楼下开始介绍我了!
I'm sorry I was a lousy boyfriend.
对不起我曾是个糟糕的男朋友.
对不起我曾经让你失望.我知道你想要的只是一个可以信赖的人...
I'm sorry I let you down. I know all you wanted was someone you could trust...
Oh, Stuart, really I can't talk about our relationship right now.
喔，斯图亚特，真的我现在不能在这儿谈我们的关系如何.
Please.
我们不应该再浪费时间了.
Maybe we weren't such a waste of time after all.
我是说，对你来讲我还是一个有用的人.你在讲什么啊?
- I mean, maybe there's a reason I was your guy.  What are you talking about?
Maybe I was supposed to help you find your guy... Leopold.
也许我可以帮助你找到你的那个朋友... Leopold.
You got to go back, Kate.
你应该回到过去, Kate.
你应该回到那儿去.
You got to go back there.
Go back?
回去?
怎么回去?
How?
You have to jump off the Brooklyn Bridge within the next 23 minutes.
你只有从布鲁克林大桥跳下去在未来的23分钟以内.
Kate? Kate?
Kate!
Kate, just look at the pictures, okay?
Kate,你看一下照片行吗?
- Is there a... a Kate McKay in the house? - Yeah.
房子里是不是有一个Kate McKay?
啊，我在这儿!Kate?
- Here I am!  Kate?
Here she is. Here she is.
她来了，她来了.
那，我就不在啰嗦了
Well, without further ado the new senior vice president...
我们纽约公司的新的副总裁.
...of our New York offices.
她来了, 女士们先生们-- Kate McKay.
Here she is, ladies and gentlemen... Kate McKay.
你没事?没事.对不起.
- You okay?  Yeah. I'm sorry.
谢谢你.特殊的入场,是吗?
- Thank you. Quite an entrance, huh?
Thank you, J.J. Thank you very much.
谢谢, J.J.谢谢你们.谢谢你们. 谢谢.
Wow.
啊，
Well...
...it's a great night.
真是一个美好的夜晚.
We here at...
我们在
CRG总是认为自己的宗旨是能够发现“大众的需求”
...CRG have always considered ourselves to be in the "Find what people want" business and at Jansen...
...you guys are in the "Make what people want" business.
而在Jansen公司,你们这些人的宗旨是总是能够满足：大众的需求“
So, imagine what we can do together.
那，可以想像如果是我们合作.
我们就可以共同去找到顾客的需要
We'll be able to find out exactly what people want...
...and make it for them.
然后一起去满足他们.
So... yeah, so our customers...
这样.... 我们的顾客...
我们的顾客，就将获得最直接的...
...will be able to get exactly...
...what they...
嗯...他们...
...they want.
...他们的需要.
和，嗯...
And, uh...
...it's a great thing to...
...这是最好的事情...
...to get what you want. Uh, it's a really good thing.
能够得到你想要的东西.这是最好的事情.
除非是你觉得你想要的不是真实的
Unless what you thought you wanted wasn't really...
...what you wanted because what you really...
你想要的因为那确实是你所...
...wanted...
...想要的
...you couldn't imagine, or you didn't think it was possible.
你简直不能想像或者根本没有想到这是可能的事
But...
但是...
...but what if someone came along who knew...
但是如果来了这么一个人他不用询问就知道
你心里在想什么?
...exactly what you wanted without asking?
They just knew. Like they could...
他就是知道.就像是他能够...
听到你心跳的声音
hear your heart beating...
或者可以感觉到你的思想.
or listen to your thoughts...
And what if they were sure of themselves...
如果他是那样的感到对自己的确定
...and they didn't have to take a poll...
还有对自己的信心
还有他爱你...
...and they loved you...
还有你却感到踌躇?
...and you hesitated?
嗯...
And...
还有.. 我必须走了.
I have to go.
I, uh...
我，...
I'm sorry, but I have to go.
我必须走了.
Kate? Kate?
Stuart, can you tell me...
斯图亚特，你可以告诉我吗
...in short, complete sentences featuring no words over two syllables...
说短点，简单点不要拖泥带水
...why exactly I am in these pictures?
为什么我在这些照片里?
- Probably not.  Try.
也许不.想想.
- Because you were there. - I wasn't.
-因为你在那儿-我不在.
我应该记得.相信我, 我应该记得-如果我在那儿.
I would remember. Believe me, I would remember if I was there.
- Because you're going to be there.  If we get there in time.
-因为你正打算去那儿.如果我们准时到那儿.
These are pictures of the past, not the future.
这些是过去的照片，不是将来.
不完全.理论上讲如果你在将来回到过去
Not exactly. Theoretically speaking if you go to the past in the future...
...then your future lies in the past.
那你的将来就存在于过去之中.
And that is a picture of you in the future in the past.
这就是照片上的你既在将来，又在过去.
我们必须跑过去了，我们走.
We have to make a run for it. Let's go.
Come on, come on.
快点，快点.
Let's go, let's go. Come on!
我们走，我们走，快点!
噢，你们在就想这个样子走了?6.80的车费，伙计.
Whoa, where the hell do you think you're going? $6.80 on the meter, pal.
It's going to close, Kate! Come on!
就要关了, Kate!快点!
女士们，先生们,请大家注意?
Ladies and gentlemen, may I have your attention?
Albany的公爵将在20分钟后
The Duke of Albany...
...will be making a very important announcement...
在这个地方
...in 20 minutes from this very stage.
作出一项重要的声明.
And I believe it shall be an announcement...
我相信这个声明能够
配合我们
...that will justify...
...the playing of a bridal waltz.
播放的婚礼华尔滋舞曲.
好了..这是最困难的一个部分.
Okay... this is the hard part.
- What? The girder.
-什么?-那个大梁.
- The girder? You have to cross the girder, Kate.
大梁?你必须走到大梁那边去, Kate.
那个大梁?
That girder?
- Stuart, I can't cross that girder. I can't go across... You love him, right?
斯图亚特，我走不到大梁那边去.-我不敢过去..-你爱他，对吧?
What?
什么?
Leopold. Leopold.
You love him, right?
你爱他，是吧?
是.
Yeah.
那就是你要知道的,现在过去.
That's all you need to know. Now go.
- You'll be fine.  Katie...
-你会没事的.-Katie...
Charlie...
查理...
- Charlie, what am I... How are you... No, don't worry about me.
查理,我该......你怎么办...别，别为我担心.
-现在, kate，现在.-现在?
- Now, Kate, now. Now?
The portal's going to close.
入口就要关闭了.
- All right. Go.
-好吧.-走.
-天哪.-哇!
- Jesus. Whoo!
Oh, God.
噢，上帝.
你可以做到.
You can do it.
Don't look down.
不要看下面.
Shit.
Charlie...
查理...
我永远爱你.
I'll love you forever.
爱你.
Love you.
It's okay.
没事的.
Lady... lady, what are you doing?
女士... 女士,你在干什么?
- Step back, lady. It's okay.
退回来，女士.-好了.
-退回来，女士.回来.女士.
Step back from there, lady. Come back, lady.
Central, be advised This is Breech Post Four.
总台，注意这是四号巡逻员.
I've got a jumper on the southwest location of the bridge.
我这儿有一个跳桥的人在大桥的西南位置.
立即出动NESU和港口救护队到这个位置.
Have a supervisor, ESU and Harbor respond to this location forthwith.
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士们，先生们
...it is with a glad heart and a bright eye that I proudly introduce...
我非常愉快的
...my beloved nephew Leopold...
自豪的介绍我的侄儿Leopold,
...Duke of Albany.
Albany公爵.
Thank you, Uncle Millard. Thank you.
谢谢.谢谢你,Millard叔叔.谢谢.
对不起，女士这是一个私人的聚会.
I'm sorry, madam, but this is a private affair.
No, you don't seem to understand.
不，你看来没有弄明白.
I need to get inside. I need to get inside right now and...
我需要进去.我需要现在就进去..
What seems to be the problem?
到底有什么事情?
- Are you Otis? Well...
你是Otis吗?好了,
...let us proceed. Please raise your glasses...
让我们继续.请大家举杯...
...so we may toast to my bride-to-be...
为我未来的新娘....
...the woman whose welfare and happiness shall be my solemn duty to maintain.
一个尽职的，能使生活更美满的女人
The future Duchess of Albany...
-噢!-未来的公爵夫人是...
Kate McKay....Kate McKay...
家族是......?
Of the McKays of...?
Massapequa.  Massapequa.
Massapequa. ...Massapequa.
I Love You.I Love You.
我爱你.我爱你.
If I caught the world
in a bottle
And everything was still
beneath the moon
Without your love,
would it shine for me?
If I was smart as Aristotle
And understood
the rings around the moon
What would it all matter
if you loved me?
Here in your arms where
the world is impossibly still
With a million dreams
to fulfill
And a matter of moments
until the dancing ends
Here in your arms when
everything seems to be clear
Not a solitary thing
would I fear
Except when this moment comes
If I caught the world
in an hourglass
Saddled up the moon
so we could ride
Until the stars grew dim
Until...
One day
you?l meet a stranger
And all the noise
is silenced in the room
to some mystery
In the moonlight
and everything shatters
known her all your life
in history
Here in your arms where
the world is impossibly still
With a million dreams
to fulfill
And a matter of moments
until the dancing ends
Here in your arms when
everything seems to be clear
Not a solitary thing
do I fear
Except when this moment
Oh, if I caught the world
in an hourglass
Saddled up the moon
and we would ride
Until the stars grew dim
Until the time
that time stands still
Until...